<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Redline Doc</title>
    <link>http://redlinedoc.com/categories/i-never-saw-that-coming/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Redline Doc</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://redlinedoc.com/categories/i-never-saw-that-coming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Cultural insensitivity</title>
      <link>http://redlinedoc.com/2012/07/cultural-insensitivity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://redlinedoc.com/2012/07/cultural-insensitivity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m glad my culture of&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.commentarymagazine.com/article/shakespeare-shylock-and-the-jews/&#34;&gt; 5700 years&lt;/a&gt; has been reduced to &amp;lsquo;good moneymaking&amp;rsquo;.  After all, I&amp;rsquo;m sure the Moses, as he descended from the mount had a marketing plan to sell little &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.commentarymagazine.com/article/shakespeare-shylock-and-the-jews/&#34;&gt;Torah&lt;/a&gt;s all over, because he was &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/19579910&#34;&gt;culturally attuned&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can hear  the clang of symbols as my &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Passover&#34;&gt;ancestors fled Egypt&lt;/a&gt; making sure they stowed the gold on their way out of the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Throughout the centuries&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.adl.org/Anti_semitism/jewsandmoney/default.asp&#34;&gt; Jews have been derided for their attentiveness to money&lt;/a&gt; and things money, often imbued with powers never given them to control monies.  &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.commentarymagazine.com/article/shakespeare-shylock-and-the-jews/&#34;&gt;Shylock&lt;/a&gt;, that most derided of Shakesperian characters is but one of many.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr Romney, do you not hear the &lt;a href=&#34;http://patrickmacmanus.wordpress.com/2011/03/13/from-gaza-listening-to-the-hoof-beats-of-history/&#34;&gt;hoofbeats of history&lt;/a&gt;?    When you suggest that the Jewish people culturally are attuned to moneymaking did you disconnect from our recent history?  The&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.calvin.edu/academic/cas/gpa/images/sturmer/sturm05.jpg&#34;&gt; images of Jews and money&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://emperors-clothes.com/antisem/naz-sov.htm&#34;&gt;world domination&lt;/a&gt; flooded German newspapers, particularly &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.calvin.edu/academic/cas/gpa/images/sturmer/ds37-47.jpg&#34; title=&#34;Racist papers of the 1930&#39;s &#34;&gt;de Sturmer&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I understand the rush for votes.  I also understand that history is less forgiving than we thought. Apparently we are slow to learn those lessons. &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikiquote.org/wiki/George_Santayana&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Those who cannot remember the past, are condemned to repeat it.&amp;ldquo; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pish tosh</title>
      <link>http://redlinedoc.com/2011/06/pish-tosh/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://redlinedoc.com/2011/06/pish-tosh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ahh my faith in the society of &lt;a href=&#34;http://washingtonexaminer.com/politics/2011/06/obama-rubs-elbows-regulatory-robber-barons&#34;&gt;robber barons &lt;/a&gt;is renewed! On the news: A fine of 156 million is levied for stealing. No jail. No restrictions just the fine at 1% of last years net.  Wow! The cost of doing business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not dismayed anymore. I&amp;rsquo;m sad. I&amp;rsquo;m sure I&amp;rsquo;m not alone. The &lt;a href=&#34;http://moneyland.time.com/2011/06/21/banks-are-hurting-its-all-relative/&#34;&gt;weasels are in the hen house &lt;/a&gt;and have eaten all the chickens and wonder why there are no eggs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More interesting than the fine is the underlying lie. The company, and apparently the big five are all involved, took money from investors, short sold the investment (this means they bet AGAINST the investor making money), told them how wonderful the packaged securities were and then laughed at them for their folly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ho Humm. Business lying as usual. Whats the news here?  We&amp;rsquo;ve suspected for some time that the SEC (Securities and Exchange Commission) was bought and paid for, but now having raped the American economy and managing to blame the poor outcome on the suckers who &lt;a href=&#34;http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;amp;ct2=us%2F0_0_s_4_0_t&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNFF0GqujJNgintdcZqpWnbTFom7HQ&amp;amp;did=e7413863b8afb6a0&amp;amp;cid=8797715370661&amp;amp;ei=zP8BTuj3LoX8ggfA98DtAg&amp;amp;rt=SEARCH&amp;amp;vm=STANDARD&amp;amp;url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.bloomberg.com%2Fnews%2F2011-06-21%2Fgensler-evolving-in-derivatives-war-sees-no-deed-go-unpunished.html&#34;&gt;bought into their racetrack scheme&lt;/a&gt;, the government fails to even slow down this juggernaut.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I agree with comedian &lt;a href=&#34;http://lewisblack.com/bio.aspx&#34;&gt;Lewis Black&lt;/a&gt; who said &amp;ldquo;You should expect of your leaders what you expect of an experienced canoe guide.  We&amp;rsquo;re going down that fork in the river and not the other because down there there&amp;rsquo;s a *#$(* waterfall!!&amp;rdquo;  What we have are disneyesque leaders pushing us &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.snopes.com/disney/films/lemmings.asp&#34;&gt;off the cliff like lemmings&lt;/a&gt;, to make a &amp;#8216;good show&amp;rsquo;.  We should preserve the banks because they&amp;rsquo;re our salvation. HAH.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I watch, from the poorest census district in the United States, not 40 miles from nearly the richest, with the realization that we have always blamed the poor for our outcomes. They&amp;rsquo;re the ones who did this. They created the financial collapse, not the liars at the banks, not the conniving realtors who sold properties they knew would never be repaid, nor the investment banks which rolled all this compost into securities, laughing at the unicorns and morons that would buy such stuff that they themselves had bet against! Imagine that.  An so they have left a trail of devastation and destruction that will take years, if ever to recover from. The folks, trusting their employers to look after them had very low social security payouts but good supplemental income from investments made by their employers  &amp;ndash;  now all vanished at the racetracks of the banking world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.quoteworld.org/quotes/3649&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;It was the best of times, it was the worst of times; it ws the age of wisdom, it was the age of foolishness; it was the epoch of belief, it was the epoch of incredulity; it was the season of Light, it was the season of Darkness; it was the spring of hope, it was the winter of despair; we had everything before us, we had nothing before us; we were all going directly to Heaven, we were all going the other way.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; I&amp;rsquo;d hope there would be some public outcry, anger at the blood in the streets. How Dickensian this has all become.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let them eat cruisers &amp;#8230;</title>
      <link>http://redlinedoc.com/2010/04/let-them-eat-cruisers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://redlinedoc.com/2010/04/let-them-eat-cruisers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The big boys at Chrysler appear to have &lt;a href=&#34;http://online.wsj.com/article/SB10001424052748704133804575197591370809782.html?mod=WSJ_newsreel_business#articleTabs_comments&#34;&gt;taken the pipe, 4 BILLION&lt;/a&gt; (with a &amp;lsquo;B&amp;rsquo; folks) in losses since exiting bankrupty! I doubt that will stop the executive piggies from snorting at the money trough in the name of needing to pay the best and brightest.&lt;br /&gt;
We need to remind ourselves that the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.glyphweb.com/arda/m/mouthofsauron.html&#34;&gt;Mouth of Sauron&lt;/a&gt; himself, the Chrysler damage control guy,  at meetings this past year said &amp;ldquo;Oh .. we put a bad engine in that car  &amp;ndash;  but  &amp;ndash;  (pregnant pause and I presume a wolfish smile), we don&amp;rsquo;t make them anymore.&amp;ldquo;  Not making one of the mechanically lousiest cars on the road is scarcely a strategy designed to win &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0071604/&#34;&gt;hearts and minds&lt;/a&gt; of Americans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The car had a sluggish start. It was very retro, very cute, very flawed.  The power train with an automatic could scarcely get the car out of its own way. Add a turbo and stickshift and it did go. Fixing the cars, it was my mechanic&amp;rsquo;s nightmare, was another thing. It would appear that the engine had been dropped into the car without regard for access. After all what fool would want to fix this?  Access to the engine required removing the right side of the car and all the steering gear there. The engine mounts blocked access to such non critical parts as the timing belt adjustment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I attended school at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.engr.uconn.edu/&#34;&gt;UCONN (University of Connecticut)&lt;/a&gt; which at the time had one of the finest civil and mechanical engineering departments in the country. I have friends from &lt;a href=&#34;http://web.mit.edu/&#34;&gt;MIT&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.caltech.edu/&#34;&gt;CALTECH&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.case.edu/&#34;&gt;CASE&lt;/a&gt; to name but a few. They seem pretty competent.  Is it possible there&amp;rsquo;s a large vacuum at Chrysler which sucks the smarts out of the engineering staff, followed closely by the moral vacuum which removes all traces of morality.   I have long thought that American ingenuity can solve most problems.  The difficulty is that American greed removes the problem solving substituting marketing glitz, &lt;a href=&#34;http://shakespeare.mit.edu/macbeth/macbeth.5.5.html&#34; title=&#34;Apologies to Shakespeare&#34;&gt;full of sound and fury, signifying, nothing. &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bonuses for bettors</title>
      <link>http://redlinedoc.com/2010/03/bonuses_for_bettors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://redlinedoc.com/2010/03/bonuses_for_bettors/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been quiet again. Probably feeling a deep recession myself, much more moral than fiscal but none the less, staying away from vocalizing what should be said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I awoke to a story this morning about Jeffrey Skilling. His lawyers want to revisit the case so poor Jeffrey, who ruined the lives not only of stockholders, but his fellow employees by lying and taking their monies would be set free. But I digress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I work in Hartford, now ranked the third poorest city of its size in the nation. Once it had a thriving downtown and people worked at department stores, in the pre-mall days, with names like G Fox and Company or Brown-Thompson and more. They probably never made much more than minimum wage but worked hard, many of them for 30 years or more and retired with small social security benefits but with a retirement plan that allowed them some leeway to visit grandchildren, keep an apartment or house and generally live a decent retired lifestyle. No high rollers here, just decent hardworking folks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spoke to one the other day, now on the verge of losing her house because she can&amp;rsquo;t make the tax payments. How? Well Jeffrey Skilling&amp;rsquo;s friends at Morgan Stanley and Lehman Brothers (and many others) took her monies to the racetrack, bet the monies on derrivatives (a fancy name for casino in the stock world). So long as everyone was making 100% returns (you do see where this is going) everyone was happy. Then the day came when someone looked and (((GASP!!!))) the emperor was naked. The whole house of cards fell and with it the retirements and savings of the folks in the North End of Hartford and elsewhere. Oh well. Not to despair. We&amp;rsquo;re so good (the Skilling-ites replied) that we need bonuses to make sure that we retain all these fine young minds. And so they did. We the people bonused the bettors. If they&amp;rsquo;d done this at a OTB window they could not have done a better job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What of my lady in the North End. She, who worked all her life gets to go on assistance. She spoke with me with tears in her eyes.   She&amp;rsquo;d never taken anything from anyone and now she was forced to accept this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not the blood thirsty sort; however, I have visions of letting Jeffrey or his ilk, loose in a field with some of the folks they fleeced. Heads on pikes. It might slow the cascade of betting other peoples monies. It might bring some cold comfort to those without heat or shelter because they lent trust and were returned fiduciary irresponsibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spoke with a 401K counselor recently about all this stealing. He of course in his snow-cones-salesman&amp;rsquo;s way assured me that this could never happen to mutual funds? Huh?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Somewhere out there I recall that fiduciary meant fiscally responsible. If we bonus these people perhaps they should pay (directly) some of those millions to those they fleeced.  An idea but hardly likely to fly. Nope. Heads on pikes I think.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Irony rides again</title>
      <link>http://redlinedoc.com/2009/08/irony-rides-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://redlinedoc.com/2009/08/irony-rides-again/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve had a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.phrases.org.uk/meanings/87600.html&#34;&gt;catbird seat&lt;/a&gt; for the construction of a new facility in the poor end of town where I work. Its a marvel of glass and concrete and steel and glass &amp;ndash; oh I DID say glass. Indeed the glass rises nearly spire like to the roof at the front of this building. Wing like, the roof soars. It is a beauty to behold. One of the many problems, probably not foreseen on this &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nature.org/wherewework/northamerica/.../connecticut/connecticutriver/&#34;&gt;ancient floodplain&lt;/a&gt; of a building site, is that water needs to go somewhere. Build a soaring roof and you have roaring drainage water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The water comes off the roof so fast that it needs a cistern to slow the flow of the water. Cisterns were installed, thermos bottle looking affairs on concrete pads around the building. Voila, problem solved. Not so fast. The waters, not seen since the times of Noah, overwhelmed even this system digging up the ground. Solution: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tennessee.gov/environment/wpc/sed_ero_controlhandbook/rr.pdf&#34;&gt;Riprap,&lt;/a&gt; stones to break up the water spilling from the cisterns from the roof. Ahh, architecture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is indeed a pretty solution, 4 to 4 &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; inch &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wesleyan.edu/ctgeology/Traprock.PDF&#34;&gt;traprock&lt;/a&gt;. Traprock has an irregular shape with sharp edges and pointy parts. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t move much. However, it is also about softball sized and easy to fit in the hand. About now there should be a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DXCbAtkgNMw&#34;&gt;D&amp;rsquo;oh&lt;/a&gt; much like Homer Simpson. Rocks. Windows. I believe the building will soon be in the glass business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has been something which when I point this out to people, step by step, they say &amp;ldquo;OH WOW&amp;rdquo;. Yea. Tinkle tinkle. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.filmsite.org/dest.html&#34;&gt;Irony rides again!&lt;/a&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Last you a lifetime!</title>
      <link>http://redlinedoc.com/2009/07/last-you-a-lifetime/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://redlinedoc.com/2009/07/last-you-a-lifetime/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I found myself unaccountably angry at statements from the auto manufacturers the other day. The mouth of Sauron from Chrysler tells us that to save money and jobs (and get a handout from Uncle Sam), that they&amp;rsquo;re dropping several lines, among them the PT Cruiser. Not much new. One of the reasons they&amp;rsquo;re dropping the cruiser is that they put a bad engine in the thing; but it sold. So what!?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what? So I&amp;rsquo;m one of the poor schleps that bought a PT Cruiser but had some misgivings about the power train. I put a lot of miles on a car, somewhere around 36000. I bought their extended warranty because it came with &amp;lsquo;lifetime&amp;rsquo; oil changes. I figured at 30-40$ a clip and I change oil monthly.  Dutifully I took the car in for changes. Once day I heard a horrible racket from the engine. It was the power steering pump, I later found out. My mechanic looked at the car and realized (he called me under the car) to see the broken front motor mount, the torn high-pressure power steering link and the torn oil line. Hmmmm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cars are for me rather like black boxes. These even -=I=- with my untrammeled vision could easily see. The oil had been changed a mere 3 days before!  The dealer never did get back to me. I stopped using the oil change service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The car will last until it dies. I keep it oiled and well fed but I know that time is not on my side. Now that its been orphaned things will only get worse. The fat cats at Chrysler will dine well and sleep without ethics. What saddens me most is that the country I love, the country I fought for, the country I raised my children in is eating itself, or rather being eaten alive by the corporations who made it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was a time when things were built to last. There was always a wink and a smile when some things had built in obsolesence. Where are the buggy whip manufacturers, the boom box makers, the 8 track fabricators .. but things were built with an eye toward building customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My next door neighbor when I was a kid used to tell stories of his dad who ran a general store in Coventry CT. One of the customers (in the late 1800&amp;rsquo;s) came in complaining about the axe he had. &amp;lsquo;Best axe I ever bought&amp;rsquo; said he, &amp;lsquo;six new heads, seven new handles. Last me a lifetime&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dead chickens. No eggs.</title>
      <link>http://redlinedoc.com/2009/06/dead-chickens-no-eggs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://redlinedoc.com/2009/06/dead-chickens-no-eggs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was recently reminded that leaving weasels in the hen house gives you a result. Alas, its dead chickens and no eggs.  Why chickens?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our economic (heaven forfend czars) have been running in and out of the hen house. I had proposed, and I&amp;rsquo;m not a gory fellow, that perhaps a few heads-on-pikes outside Lehman Brothers might have curtailed the mad stealing that goes on. Yes, I&amp;rsquo;m a victim too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each day I read of the glorious rounds of &lt;a href=&#34;http://http://www.alternet.org/story/140327/?page=entire&#34;&gt;in the front out the back door&lt;/a&gt; dealing at the SEC with Larry Summers or the folks at Chrysler or GM who revel in the bailout, glory in bankruptcy.  A few days ago the VP of Chrysler said in effect sorry folks we made some lousy cars, like the PT Crusier, it had a lousy engine but they sold!&amp;#8230;. and I an owner of one of those lumps of clay!  There is some &lt;a href=&#34;http://blogs.reuters.com/reuters-dealzone/2009/06/02/bankruptcy-means-never-having-to-say-sorry/&#34;&gt;chutzpah in the GM&lt;/a&gt; folks managing NOT to take any responsibility for anything. Its the fault of unions, economy, dealers, stockholders, manufacturers of parts but no no no not GM. They didn&amp;rsquo;t make cars that didn&amp;rsquo;t run, engines that failed for obvious reasons, cars that fell apart nearly on the lots,  no no no not them. Its someone else&amp;rsquo;s fault. Those same donkeys are going to be rebuilding the same cars but with our monies. What a way to go. Take a risk. Do a lousy job. Get a bailout!    Hmmm is there a DD-285/7448  that -=I=- can get to fill in for my share?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indeed all the folks are all white-washed now. Not to worry. Stole a few million in pension funds from old folks to gamble away with 100:1 odds? Didn&amp;rsquo;t see it coming? Naah not to worry Mr Weasel, here are the keys.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what. They&amp;rsquo;re old. They didn&amp;rsquo;t need the eggs anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>