<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Redline Doc</title>
    <link>http://redlinedoc.com/tags/executive&#43;compensation/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Redline Doc</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://redlinedoc.com/tags/executive&#43;compensation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Let them eat cruisers &amp;#8230;</title>
      <link>http://redlinedoc.com/2010/04/let-them-eat-cruisers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://redlinedoc.com/2010/04/let-them-eat-cruisers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The big boys at Chrysler appear to have &lt;a href=&#34;http://online.wsj.com/article/SB10001424052748704133804575197591370809782.html?mod=WSJ_newsreel_business#articleTabs_comments&#34;&gt;taken the pipe, 4 BILLION&lt;/a&gt; (with a &amp;lsquo;B&amp;rsquo; folks) in losses since exiting bankrupty! I doubt that will stop the executive piggies from snorting at the money trough in the name of needing to pay the best and brightest.&lt;br /&gt;
We need to remind ourselves that the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.glyphweb.com/arda/m/mouthofsauron.html&#34;&gt;Mouth of Sauron&lt;/a&gt; himself, the Chrysler damage control guy,  at meetings this past year said &amp;ldquo;Oh .. we put a bad engine in that car  &amp;ndash;  but  &amp;ndash;  (pregnant pause and I presume a wolfish smile), we don&amp;rsquo;t make them anymore.&amp;ldquo;  Not making one of the mechanically lousiest cars on the road is scarcely a strategy designed to win &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0071604/&#34;&gt;hearts and minds&lt;/a&gt; of Americans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The car had a sluggish start. It was very retro, very cute, very flawed.  The power train with an automatic could scarcely get the car out of its own way. Add a turbo and stickshift and it did go. Fixing the cars, it was my mechanic&amp;rsquo;s nightmare, was another thing. It would appear that the engine had been dropped into the car without regard for access. After all what fool would want to fix this?  Access to the engine required removing the right side of the car and all the steering gear there. The engine mounts blocked access to such non critical parts as the timing belt adjustment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I attended school at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.engr.uconn.edu/&#34;&gt;UCONN (University of Connecticut)&lt;/a&gt; which at the time had one of the finest civil and mechanical engineering departments in the country. I have friends from &lt;a href=&#34;http://web.mit.edu/&#34;&gt;MIT&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.caltech.edu/&#34;&gt;CALTECH&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.case.edu/&#34;&gt;CASE&lt;/a&gt; to name but a few. They seem pretty competent.  Is it possible there&amp;rsquo;s a large vacuum at Chrysler which sucks the smarts out of the engineering staff, followed closely by the moral vacuum which removes all traces of morality.   I have long thought that American ingenuity can solve most problems.  The difficulty is that American greed removes the problem solving substituting marketing glitz, &lt;a href=&#34;http://shakespeare.mit.edu/macbeth/macbeth.5.5.html&#34; title=&#34;Apologies to Shakespeare&#34;&gt;full of sound and fury, signifying, nothing. &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bonuses for bettors</title>
      <link>http://redlinedoc.com/2010/03/bonuses_for_bettors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://redlinedoc.com/2010/03/bonuses_for_bettors/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been quiet again. Probably feeling a deep recession myself, much more moral than fiscal but none the less, staying away from vocalizing what should be said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I awoke to a story this morning about Jeffrey Skilling. His lawyers want to revisit the case so poor Jeffrey, who ruined the lives not only of stockholders, but his fellow employees by lying and taking their monies would be set free. But I digress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I work in Hartford, now ranked the third poorest city of its size in the nation. Once it had a thriving downtown and people worked at department stores, in the pre-mall days, with names like G Fox and Company or Brown-Thompson and more. They probably never made much more than minimum wage but worked hard, many of them for 30 years or more and retired with small social security benefits but with a retirement plan that allowed them some leeway to visit grandchildren, keep an apartment or house and generally live a decent retired lifestyle. No high rollers here, just decent hardworking folks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spoke to one the other day, now on the verge of losing her house because she can&amp;rsquo;t make the tax payments. How? Well Jeffrey Skilling&amp;rsquo;s friends at Morgan Stanley and Lehman Brothers (and many others) took her monies to the racetrack, bet the monies on derrivatives (a fancy name for casino in the stock world). So long as everyone was making 100% returns (you do see where this is going) everyone was happy. Then the day came when someone looked and (((GASP!!!))) the emperor was naked. The whole house of cards fell and with it the retirements and savings of the folks in the North End of Hartford and elsewhere. Oh well. Not to despair. We&amp;rsquo;re so good (the Skilling-ites replied) that we need bonuses to make sure that we retain all these fine young minds. And so they did. We the people bonused the bettors. If they&amp;rsquo;d done this at a OTB window they could not have done a better job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What of my lady in the North End. She, who worked all her life gets to go on assistance. She spoke with me with tears in her eyes.   She&amp;rsquo;d never taken anything from anyone and now she was forced to accept this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not the blood thirsty sort; however, I have visions of letting Jeffrey or his ilk, loose in a field with some of the folks they fleeced. Heads on pikes. It might slow the cascade of betting other peoples monies. It might bring some cold comfort to those without heat or shelter because they lent trust and were returned fiduciary irresponsibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spoke with a 401K counselor recently about all this stealing. He of course in his snow-cones-salesman&amp;rsquo;s way assured me that this could never happen to mutual funds? Huh?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Somewhere out there I recall that fiduciary meant fiscally responsible. If we bonus these people perhaps they should pay (directly) some of those millions to those they fleeced.  An idea but hardly likely to fly. Nope. Heads on pikes I think.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>