<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Redline Doc</title>
    <link>http://redlinedoc.com/tags/poor-insurance/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Redline Doc</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://redlinedoc.com/tags/poor-insurance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Again and again</title>
      <link>http://redlinedoc.com/2009/08/again-and-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://redlinedoc.com/2009/08/again-and-again/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Why can&amp;rsquo;t we pay for health care for everyone? Why is it that is this country we have such a divide? Is it our puritanical upbringing which says work hard and you&amp;rsquo;ll get your rewards?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sadly folks, the Puritan&amp;rsquo;s didn&amp;rsquo;t have it all that wonderfully. Life was hard but it was short. There were no antibiotics, no x-rays, no casts, no real surgery (with anesthesia). Hospitals were to be avoided as pest houses and physicians themselves at the time knew they did little for their patients. Some cures were probably worse than the diseases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we have modernized medicine, why can&amp;rsquo;t we modernize the way we provide care for our citizens. Why do we in the land of the brave, home of the free, live with a 3rd world medical care system. Sure people come here. The Sultan of Brunei came here and got wonderful care. M. D., a fictional name, in the north end of Hartford got &lt;a href=&#34;Http://www.urbandictionary.com/define.php?term=turfed&#34;&gt;turfed&lt;/a&gt;. Hmmm. Would the divide and provision of care have to do with money?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indeed it does. The wheels grind exceeding slowly for those with limited funding.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All the Michaels are dead...</title>
      <link>http://redlinedoc.com/2009/08/all-the-michaels-are-dead/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://redlinedoc.com/2009/08/all-the-michaels-are-dead/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How did we allow the discussion to move away from health to how we should save the health insurance industry? How did that conversation move from a public healthy option to saving the profits of some of the most profitable companies in the world?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As there is increasing &lt;a href=&#34;http://sensen-no-sen.blogspot.com/2009/07/health-care-oligopoly-and-real-weight.html&#34;&gt;talk in Washington about the AMA &lt;/a&gt; time clicks by. And to whom are the insurance companies responsible? Ahhh shareholders, the same folks who brought us the current bank debacle, to whom we the people pay extravagant sums so that they can support CEO&amp;rsquo;s in a style to which they&amp;rsquo;d like to become accustomed. As there is continued agglomeration of insurers, they flock together, eat each other, thereby decreasing real market competition, in the guise of bringing lower cost to the consumer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In medicine we speak for the patient. In insurance they speak for the money. There&amp;rsquo;s an inherent split here. When it comes down to it, shall we authorize care OR shall we make 0.02 for the stockholder, the stockholder and CEO options always win out. Duplicity is the name of the game. When &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nhc.noaa.gov/1992andrew.html&#34;&gt;Hurricane Andrew&lt;/a&gt; roared across the South Florida Peninsula devastating the area. Aetna group was the major insurer holding more than 4 billion dollars in losses. That past year they golden parachuted their worthy CEO for 987 MILLION dollars (or there abouts) and then cried the blues that they didn&amp;rsquo;t have monies for claims. Hmmmm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I personally have run into the dealings of insurers. Serveral years ago one of the Connecticut health insurers sent out a note that all billing should henceforth be sent to a POB in Enfield. We all did send claims there and as weeks went by and no claims information was forthcoming, we were told that the claims were lost or that they should be re-submitted. Whoops. Someone bad in the company made an error and there is no POB in Enfield for our claims. We&amp;rsquo;re really sorry but you&amp;rsquo;ll have to re-submit them all over again. Hmmmm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve had several friends who&amp;rsquo;ve suffered death at the hands of insurers, not in any direct sort of way but the usual games playing with existing conditions and difficult to access portals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Working in a safety net group we see patients bounced from one provider to another, mostly based on non paying insurances. I think most of us are insulted when the insurers talk about the Medicare program, and how it fails to work. It succeeds with a 5% overhead, a draconian fraud unit, and coverage that most of us envy. Are there faults? Are there fixes to be made? Of course. We can in one swoop, make our system succeed. It needs a government backed program, devoid of usurious profits, not socialism, just good medicine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We need to recenter the discussion, not about death notes but about how to prevent the needless deaths from an unwieldy bloated system which spends much of its monies not on patient well being but on corporate well being. Straight speak or soon, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0066495/&#34;&gt;all the Michaels&lt;/a&gt; will be dead&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Just want to dip my beak ...</title>
      <link>http://redlinedoc.com/2009/07/just-want-to-dip-my-beak/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://redlinedoc.com/2009/07/just-want-to-dip-my-beak/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Strange you say.  Governor Rell (I&amp;rsquo;m a yankee) just vetoed Sustinet. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.healthcare4every1.org/site/DocServer/sustinet_proposal.pdf?docID=541&#34;&gt;Sustinet&lt;/a&gt;? Sustinet was a plan to insure every citizen in Connecticut starting with the most vulnerable, including state employees and rolling in small businesses and non-profits to make a large coverage group competing with private insurance companies for benefits and coverages. No one would be forced to enter Sustinet (other than the current state medicaid/safetynet and employees) and it would have to stand on its own merit. It was broadly supported and overwhelmingly voted in both senate and house chambers in the state.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why veto it? &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ct.gov/governor/&#34;&gt;Governor Rell&lt;/a&gt; seems to have forgotten some history here. In the 1700&amp;rsquo;s the citizens of Connecticut recognizing that they didn&amp;rsquo;t want to replicate the Dickensian debtor prisons of England, established havens for those to sick or unable to work; town farms. The town farms were by no means a happy haven but residents there worked on the farm as they could, helped to be self sustaining, had some funding from the Selectman&amp;rsquo;s budget in the town and had food and clothings and housing and medical care. This, from the compassionate citizens of Connecticut. Fast forward. When larger government programs superseded the Town Farm System, the program became State Aid to General Assistance (SAGA) one of the safety net programs here in Connecticut.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No one wants to see SAGA patients. Getting referrals from primary care (I work in an &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cms.hhs.gov/center/fqhc.asp&#34;&gt;FQHC&lt;/a&gt;) to tertiary or upper level care is nearly impossible. SAGA pays poorly for advanced care and since its coverage mostly (a devilish word) is for poor folk; Who cares. The devil in the mostly is that folks who have worked all their lives but had some dreadful disease may find themselves on SAGA. Folks who have a sickness in the family, monies wiped out by the vagaries of the current &amp;ldquo;he who has the gold makes the rules insurance system&amp;rdquo; may find themselves on SAGA. The list goes on. The poor line up and are anointed with the least of the least.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sustinet looks in ways to fix this, to level the playing field by making no distinction between rich and poor by allowing all access to health care. Bah Humbug they should pull up their bootstraps, you say. WHO will pull up the bootstraps. My 24 year old daughter recently fell into the hole between parental coverage and no coverage from work. Luckily she had her health. Needed medications, however, consumed a fair bite of her savings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whats with the beak dipping? Governor Rell is a leftover from the Rowland administration here in Connecticut. She distanced herself from John Rowland (who spent some time waiting for a better paying government job &amp;ndash; quel suprise!). Republican administrations believe that business will make it all perfect. That the shareholder marketplace will bring equity and equanimity to the medical system. Each of the stakeholders will &amp;ldquo;dip his beak&amp;rdquo; only taking a fair share of the monies, pleasing the boards and CEO&amp;rsquo;s. I think this more akin to crows feasting at the carcass. There isn&amp;rsquo;t much money and pleasing the shareholders never improved wellness. There is a finite supply of monies and pleasing the CEO&amp;rsquo;s and padding their golden parachutes never helped struggling parents with sick children. Dipping their beaks, sucking up the juice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ahh for sure, all that will be left of Sustinet will be the bones, no juice, no meat, no insurance, no coverage. And the fat cats will be daubing their beaks with linen napkins.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Death by insurance</title>
      <link>http://redlinedoc.com/2009/06/death-by-insurance/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://redlinedoc.com/2009/06/death-by-insurance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I lost another, friend. Death by insurance read the certificate, or so it should have. Geno was a kind fellow, gentle soul, never made lots of money but found himself suddenly underemployed, a polite term for being older and getting paid for fewer than 20 hours a week, then finding there is no health insurance&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok, you think. Let this guy pull himself up by the bootstraps. He did. He got a second job. Still no insurance. Then he got Diabetes. Oops. Its not quite like a third job because you pay them instead of getting paid. You work harder. The doc says you should have less stress. Ok. I&amp;rsquo;m working a job to pay the insurance and another to pay for food, now I have to pay rent because the diabetes job just doesn&amp;rsquo;t bring in enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oops.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now you can be on state sponsored insurance, some of the time. You feel really terrible. He did. He worked all his life and was always responsible. Now he&amp;rsquo;s a ward of the state and working.  He gets headaches. He&amp;rsquo;s not feeling well. One day he falls. He goes to a doctor but they can&amp;rsquo;t see him because his limited HMO insurance wants him to see a doctor 40 miles south. He bucks the system but there are not many alternatives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally he gets an appointment with neurology.  He has a grade 4 astrocytoma; not a good prognosis. Although he has insurance for this and has coverage, because of his limitations (he has memory lapses and poor focus) after the tumor is primarily removed,  he often forgets to take his medications or takes them improperly. Insurance has no use for home visits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He slips. He has difficulties. The secondary job is history. The primary job lays him off. He&amp;rsquo;s now totally on the HMO. They say he&amp;rsquo;s ok free living. He has slips and fall. He&amp;rsquo;s ok free living. He forgets his medications. He&amp;rsquo;s ok free living. He asks for assist but they say he&amp;rsquo;s not elegible on this cheaper chicken HMO insurance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He died yesterday. Now the HMO is off the hook. No more insurance payments. No doctor visits. No Gene. Seems like a good system. Death by insurance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lest you think this is an isolated incident -&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two years ago a friend of mine, a retailer, sucessful in business but a small retailer, began to have urinary tract pain. He had no health insurance because at more than 1500$ a month it was more than he could afford. Additionally, that amount was for catastrophic insurance, you see, as a child he&amp;rsquo;d had bladder problems and every insurance company pro-rated him.  Finally he gets insurance. He&amp;rsquo;s had, what he thinks, is a bladder infection. Its been so severe that occasionally he sleeps in a bath tub with warm waters.  Small catch. There&amp;rsquo;s a 90 day waiting period.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He goes to his doctor who, as he&amp;rsquo;d suspected, sends him to urology. They want to examine his bladder and because of prior difficulties with anatomy need to do this in a hospital. There&amp;rsquo;s this 90 day thing. We wait. He&amp;rsquo;s more comfortable but of course not better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bell rings. Its a bladder tumor. They biopsy &amp;#8211; perhaps benign, although most are not. It is benign it seems. But theres a second troubling spot next to it. Not benign. The tumor is resected, he starts chemo and radiation and everyone is hopeful. There are all sorts of limits to this insurance policy he has &amp;#8211; so greater exploration, whole body films and the like, aren&amp;rsquo;t done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two months forward, he&amp;rsquo;s a bit dizzy and falls. There is an ominous cracking sound in his neck. There&amp;rsquo;s a baseball sized tumor there. Now we do more work up. Its a metatastasis. Alas it was a death knell. When removed and the neck repaired a shower of tumors widely spread show up.  After an enormous fight he choses to let go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No more store. No more employees. No more friend. These tumors when seen early are frequently non-fatal. With time the outcomes are more dire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Death by insurance.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>