<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Redline Doc</title>
    <link>http://redlinedoc.com/tags/monday/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Redline Doc</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://redlinedoc.com/tags/monday/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Its Monday -- everybody works on Monday</title>
      <link>http://redlinedoc.com/2009/07/its-monday-everybody-works-on-monday/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://redlinedoc.com/2009/07/its-monday-everybody-works-on-monday/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;That line from the movie &amp;ldquo;Dave&amp;rdquo; would be poignant if it were not so sad here . Most of the people I see want to work &amp;ndash; but there is no work. &amp;ldquo;Work was something that used to exist&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; Jean Sheppard &amp;ndash; and he was talking about the &amp;ldquo;Great Depression&amp;rdquo;. Alas it was neither great nor did we learn from it. But I digress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday one of my patients arrived all smiles and cheery; yes.. he just got a job. A real job in a field (food service) he wanted to work in. There&amp;rsquo;s something radiant about someone who just got a job, a glow and an aura about them. He had been jobless for nearly 1 &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; years, looking looking but not finding much of anything. A sniff a lead and he was overjoyed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hear much talk about how the poor make themselves that way. I see something quite different. I go to the stores in the neighborhood where change is made poorly and incorrectly. At first I thought this an oversight but it happens so frequently that I realized that this is a way of doing business to increase profits, since many don&amp;rsquo;t check the change. There is loansharking for food, an egregious plot on the poor where 30$ in groceries on Thursday becomes 60$ (or more) on Monday. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t need much enforcement since there really isn&amp;rsquo;t much alternative place to go. Additionally the stores carry such small cans of items (2 ravioli in a can), that the prices end up enormous for minimal nutritional value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Work is hard to find in this poor urban area. Transportation is available but not always convenient. There are dangers, the indolent prey on the poor. There aren&amp;rsquo;t many but ripoffs and knockdowns occur regularly. Most people travel with one hand free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My guy. All smiles. He&amp;rsquo;s looking forward to work. I think most are. Its depressing being marked &amp;ldquo;poor&amp;rdquo; and then no places to work. Poor areas become poorer. Business shys away from the area. Poor areas become poorer yet. The spiral continues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wish that all the folks here could feel the joy &amp;ndash; pleasure &amp;ndash; of work, of a job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its Monday. Everyone SHOULD work on Monday&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>