<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Redline Doc</title>
    <link>http://redlinedoc.com/tags/emergency-room/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Redline Doc</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://redlinedoc.com/tags/emergency-room/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Turfed too</title>
      <link>http://redlinedoc.com/2009/08/turfed-too/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://redlinedoc.com/2009/08/turfed-too/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It amazes me that in the land of&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2007/08/12/opinion/12sun1.html&#34;&gt; the best healthcare&lt;/a&gt; we&amp;rsquo;re more in the business of denying care than providing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I get a call the other day that a kid has stepped on a piece of glass. Its off hours but I say &amp;ldquo;sure, bring him in, I&amp;rsquo;ll take a look&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A pale frightened 13y/o arrives at the clinic with parents. Apparently yesterday he jumped up off a picnic table (in the way that 13 year old males do) and sprang directly onto a wine glass lying on the ground. The glass shattered into the bottom of his foot. The parents, correctly, take him to the nearest emergency room. He waits approximately 3 &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; hours since its &amp;ldquo;only a bleeding foot&amp;rdquo;. Xrays show glass in the wound and the physician diagnoses tendon injuries to the tendons of the toes. Ahh, you say, a case for the surgeons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not so fast. He has a state option child health insurance. They sew up the foot (with the glass inside) and direct him to a private practice clinic the following day. He continues to bleed, slowly, through the night. Mom and dad pack him off to the local recommended doctor only to find that he (nor most others) do not accept this insurance. They are tempted to return to the emergency room but call me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He cannot be treated here. He needs advanced care which we cannot offer to him. I make some calls with the assistance of our pediatrician. He&amp;rsquo;s transferred to a tertiary care facility. By 4PM he&amp;rsquo;s in an operating room and being cared for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What went wrong? Why didn&amp;rsquo;t the emergency room transfer him inter-hospital when they realized they had a severe injury they couldn&amp;rsquo;t handle? Why did they refer him through out patient when clearly there was no real outpatient option?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Insurance. When the insurance pays so poorly that even the most basic of services are covered but lose money, then the hospitals, left to chose to bleed monies or to restrict services chose the latter. In the land of &amp;#8216;the best healthcare&amp;rdquo; we are forced into rationing that healthcare based not on need, not on priorities but on the needs of the stockholders of insurance companies.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>