<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Redline Doc</title>
    <link>http://redlinedoc.com/tags/ethics/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Redline Doc</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://redlinedoc.com/tags/ethics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Cultural insensitivity</title>
      <link>http://redlinedoc.com/2012/07/cultural-insensitivity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://redlinedoc.com/2012/07/cultural-insensitivity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m glad my culture of&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.commentarymagazine.com/article/shakespeare-shylock-and-the-jews/&#34;&gt; 5700 years&lt;/a&gt; has been reduced to &amp;lsquo;good moneymaking&amp;rsquo;.  After all, I&amp;rsquo;m sure the Moses, as he descended from the mount had a marketing plan to sell little &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.commentarymagazine.com/article/shakespeare-shylock-and-the-jews/&#34;&gt;Torah&lt;/a&gt;s all over, because he was &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/19579910&#34;&gt;culturally attuned&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can hear  the clang of symbols as my &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Passover&#34;&gt;ancestors fled Egypt&lt;/a&gt; making sure they stowed the gold on their way out of the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Throughout the centuries&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.adl.org/Anti_semitism/jewsandmoney/default.asp&#34;&gt; Jews have been derided for their attentiveness to money&lt;/a&gt; and things money, often imbued with powers never given them to control monies.  &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.commentarymagazine.com/article/shakespeare-shylock-and-the-jews/&#34;&gt;Shylock&lt;/a&gt;, that most derided of Shakesperian characters is but one of many.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr Romney, do you not hear the &lt;a href=&#34;http://patrickmacmanus.wordpress.com/2011/03/13/from-gaza-listening-to-the-hoof-beats-of-history/&#34;&gt;hoofbeats of history&lt;/a&gt;?    When you suggest that the Jewish people culturally are attuned to moneymaking did you disconnect from our recent history?  The&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.calvin.edu/academic/cas/gpa/images/sturmer/sturm05.jpg&#34;&gt; images of Jews and money&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://emperors-clothes.com/antisem/naz-sov.htm&#34;&gt;world domination&lt;/a&gt; flooded German newspapers, particularly &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.calvin.edu/academic/cas/gpa/images/sturmer/ds37-47.jpg&#34; title=&#34;Racist papers of the 1930&#39;s &#34;&gt;de Sturmer&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I understand the rush for votes.  I also understand that history is less forgiving than we thought. Apparently we are slow to learn those lessons. &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikiquote.org/wiki/George_Santayana&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Those who cannot remember the past, are condemned to repeat it.&amp;ldquo; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scammed again!</title>
      <link>http://redlinedoc.com/2012/03/scammed-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://redlinedoc.com/2012/03/scammed-again/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently I sought to upgrade from my &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.att.com/dsl&#34;&gt;DSL service &lt;/a&gt;which we&amp;rsquo;ve had since 1998 or thereabouts, finding that the current (supposedly) &lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;728&lt;/sub&gt; was really &lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;284&lt;/sub&gt; on a recent billing. Its not easy upgrading.  Since we took &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slate.com/articles/news_and_politics/jurisprudence/2007/01/bellwether.html&#34;&gt;M aBell&lt;/a&gt; (you do remember the good old &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wPYN1nk-fIA&#34; title=&#34;from: The President&#39;s Analyst&#34;&gt;AT&amp;amp;T &lt;/a&gt;?) and made it many pieces.  Its rather like the &lt;a href=&#34;http://rogerebert.suntimes.com/apps/pbcs.dll/article?AID=/19990806/REVIEWS/908060303&#34;&gt;Iron Giant&lt;/a&gt;, who reassembles himself from the blown apart pieces. He, on the other had is for good.  This, more like the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=do0x-Egc6oA&#34;&gt;evil empire&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adventurous and with some time, I call the service part of my current DSL provider only to be lost in an automated system that once in, is difficult to escape, or in my case, so insistent on one course that I could not re-enter the system.  Desperate, I decided to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sing365.com/music/lyric.nsf/lie-lie-lie-lyrics-system-of-a-down/4861f147eeb08f0848257384002b1fc4&#34;&gt;lie to the system&lt;/a&gt; and it immediately sent me to a human.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I fared not much better since the human could not understand why I wasn&amp;rsquo;t happy and didn&amp;rsquo;t want all the &lt;a href=&#34;http://idioms.thefreedictionary.com/bells+and+whistles&#34;&gt;bells and whistles&lt;/a&gt; services they were offering . It&amp;rsquo;s rather like getting a car, you want wheels , doors and some amenities; they want to sell you upgraded chrome or something the size of a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fprado.com/armorsite/abrams.htm&#34;&gt;Abrams M1 tank&lt;/a&gt;.  Sometimes I feel like a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.com/imgres?start=188&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;biw=1280&amp;amp;bih=909&amp;amp;tbm=isch&amp;amp;prmd=imvns&amp;amp;tbnid=QNz16RTNldQ1LM:&amp;amp;imgrefurl=http://sykeswrites.wordpress.com/category/fresh-fare/play/&amp;amp;docid=tvYCVF3kv3tXPM&amp;amp;imgurl=http://sykeswrites.files.wordpress.com/2010/04/tracks01.jpg%253Fw%253D470&amp;amp;w=424&amp;amp;h=283&amp;amp;ei=QqZPT6qgNMbY0QH0xLzwDQ&amp;amp;zoom=1&#34;&gt;train on a parallel track or parallel universe&lt;/a&gt; and no matter what, I can&amp;rsquo;t jump from one to the other; but, I digress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, the fourth human says you need U-verse service. Oh? I do?.  She explained to me how much faster all this would be.  She also thought this was FTTP (Fiber to the premises) when I asked several times.  My location is about 550 yards from the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thecentraloffice.com/&#34;&gt;Central Office (CO)&lt;/a&gt; although she said that didn&amp;rsquo;t matter any more. I set an appointment, rubbing my hands anticipating &lt;sup&gt;18&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt; (or maybe better!!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The technician arrived.  He said he had to do some testing and so would DISCONNECT the service which was currently running, and I might add never to reappear again.  He came back several minutes later, all the services phone and internet down, announcing they&amp;rsquo;d have to get another (different truck different division) out there, sometime.  I&amp;rsquo;m glad he didn&amp;rsquo;t use the word soon.  I had a family member at the house who also happens to be very technically able and works in the server maintenance field; not unknowledgeable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gone. Truck, driver, service and when I called they said the installation was &amp;lsquo;in progress&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t. They have an 1830 call rollover in this division. Next day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I call. They still insist this is being fixed and they have to wait for the incoming ticket.  How, by the way do I like my service.  ????  Ok.  I can take a joke.  I wait a few hours. Each of the meat shields the company has put in my way of getting to a person of knowledge says &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m really sorry your&amp;rsquo;re having this trouble&amp;rdquo; but has no helpful actions available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tick tock. We&amp;rsquo;re coming up on a weekend when nothing will get done.  I call in vain hope that a human may be able to hook something up.   The phones are back on line mysteriously.   The human who finally helps says they&amp;rsquo;re really sorry and they&amp;rsquo;ll put it all together on Saturday Morning.  The set up guys are really nice, telling us to call support for the IP addresses and ranges for the static IP&amp;rsquo;s which we&amp;rsquo;ve had these last 14 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m on and off the phone.  The support line tells me that they don&amp;rsquo;t have that I need to call &lt;a href=&#34;https://buy-connectech.att.com/ctcomm/home/index.jsp&#34; title=&#34;Scam Central&#34;&gt;ATT ConnectTech&lt;/a&gt;.   I call.  The scam begins.  You can sign up for one time 5 day service for 149$ or 15$/month 12 month minimum billed to a credit card.  Sorry, we&amp;rsquo;re not part of that phone company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;News to me!  I &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.phrases.org.uk/meanings/pony-up.html&#34;&gt;pony up&lt;/a&gt;, figuring I&amp;rsquo;ll be able to access my system.  No. No. No. Not at all. The Level 2 tech, who is very nice gives me a netmask for a Category C netblock (wow, category C, I don&amp;rsquo;t think that IBM has a cat C netmask) .. but wow, ok.  I might add, not only is it wrong, but it also, of course, doesn&amp;rsquo;t work. The IP and netmask addresses, close but not right either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m tired, angry, frustrated and feel very much taken. AT&amp;amp;T has made my life hellish without much work on their part.   I try, again the U-verse support. This time I get a &lt;a href=&#34;http://cio.ittoolbox.com/groups/strategy-planning/it-workforce-management-sp/standards-for-level-1-2-and-3-support-2862755&#34;&gt;Level 1 support&lt;/a&gt; who says, oh .. you need Level 2.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The information is supplied. &lt;a href=&#34;http://witchstead.wordpress.com/2010/05/26/dawn-breaks-over-marblehea/&#34;&gt;Dawn breaks over the computer.&lt;/a&gt;  I&amp;rsquo;ve been &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.psychologytoday.com/collections/201111/scammed/dont-get-ripped&#34;&gt;scammed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://getsatisfaction.com/att/topics/scammed_by_at_t_u_verse_contract_salesman_then_by_at_t&#34;&gt;by AT&amp;amp;T&lt;/a&gt; yet again.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>it couldn&#39;t hurt .. or could it</title>
      <link>http://redlinedoc.com/2010/10/it-couldnt-hurt-or-could-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://redlinedoc.com/2010/10/it-couldnt-hurt-or-could-it/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been watching with interest the current Republican party dance around repeal of the Healthcare insurance legislation just passed.  Its a sad bit of badly made political salad with very little for those who need health insurance, a guaranteed business for the insurance companies (universal sign up), &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slate.com/id/2224621/&#34; title=&#34;Big Pharma Billy Tauzin&#34;&gt;guaranteed pharma profits (no pharma negotiation) &lt;/a&gt;and extension of the market for about 40% of those who are still uncovered or uninsured.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;State legislatures, not to be overlooked are trying their best to carve themselves in our out of the new Heatlhcare bill by blocking advances or by shouting states rights.  With hard economic times, its easy to get voters to hear the shouting but miss the salient points.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve missed the boat, again. Smoke and mirrors and distraction reign supreme. The emperor, or his bill, have no clothes. This does not cover a majority of the uninsured. I&amp;rsquo;m waiting to see how those who are unemployed, now some approaching the 2 year mark, will pay for this bit of fluff.  The state&amp;rsquo;s assistance systems were already at a foundering point and shoving the burden to physicians and hospitals for the under and uninsured will only exacerbate the problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a bit of shuck and drag going on here. We&amp;rsquo;re told that we need to work to pass this. We&amp;rsquo;re told it will bankrupt us. We&amp;rsquo;re told this is socialism at its worst.  Socialism?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today one of the walking wounded comes to the clinic. She works 40-50 hours a week, full time  she&amp;rsquo;s told, at one of the local hospitals. To expedite services the hospital contracts out its housekeeping. The firm, to keep profits ripe,  they don&amp;rsquo;t pay insurance.  Hmm. Ok. We took what was a paid in-house position, took away the benefits, hired the same folks to do the same job so that the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=p220yi2VOj8&#34; title=&#34;I was gonna  be an engineer &#34;&gt;profits would stay as high as maybe &lt;/a&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I digress. Here&amp;rsquo;s a full time working person with no insurance.  How is a public option for her, socialism?  From where I sit, we pay into the medicare system.  We pay it in wages and taxes and reap a long term benefit devoid of the need for stockholders to benefit. Although an inconstant fiduciary, generally governments have handled trust funds much better than banks or insurance companies, always looking to the next gaming table, ripening the profits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we allow the loud shouts to take back the minimal advances, and I agree its far from perfect, we&amp;rsquo;ll end up with still more uninsured.  The hidden cost of the &amp;lsquo;uninsured&amp;rsquo; long patched over by draining high end payments from private insurers into the unbalanced pot is at an end. The insurance blokes, have cut off that avenue. The uninsured now go to emergency rooms, expensive care, and not much of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Emphasis from the Healthcare Plan was on primary care, extending to patients the ability to see and to find competent expert medical care. If we persist at deconstructing the fragile imperfect house, we&amp;rsquo;ll have but a very expensive house of cards fallen loosely and very expensively apart.  Threats of Medicare cuts are more thunder than substance. We do need government to help us. Watch carefully.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let them eat cruisers &amp;#8230;</title>
      <link>http://redlinedoc.com/2010/04/let-them-eat-cruisers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://redlinedoc.com/2010/04/let-them-eat-cruisers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The big boys at Chrysler appear to have &lt;a href=&#34;http://online.wsj.com/article/SB10001424052748704133804575197591370809782.html?mod=WSJ_newsreel_business#articleTabs_comments&#34;&gt;taken the pipe, 4 BILLION&lt;/a&gt; (with a &amp;lsquo;B&amp;rsquo; folks) in losses since exiting bankrupty! I doubt that will stop the executive piggies from snorting at the money trough in the name of needing to pay the best and brightest.&lt;br /&gt;
We need to remind ourselves that the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.glyphweb.com/arda/m/mouthofsauron.html&#34;&gt;Mouth of Sauron&lt;/a&gt; himself, the Chrysler damage control guy,  at meetings this past year said &amp;ldquo;Oh .. we put a bad engine in that car  &amp;ndash;  but  &amp;ndash;  (pregnant pause and I presume a wolfish smile), we don&amp;rsquo;t make them anymore.&amp;ldquo;  Not making one of the mechanically lousiest cars on the road is scarcely a strategy designed to win &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0071604/&#34;&gt;hearts and minds&lt;/a&gt; of Americans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The car had a sluggish start. It was very retro, very cute, very flawed.  The power train with an automatic could scarcely get the car out of its own way. Add a turbo and stickshift and it did go. Fixing the cars, it was my mechanic&amp;rsquo;s nightmare, was another thing. It would appear that the engine had been dropped into the car without regard for access. After all what fool would want to fix this?  Access to the engine required removing the right side of the car and all the steering gear there. The engine mounts blocked access to such non critical parts as the timing belt adjustment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I attended school at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.engr.uconn.edu/&#34;&gt;UCONN (University of Connecticut)&lt;/a&gt; which at the time had one of the finest civil and mechanical engineering departments in the country. I have friends from &lt;a href=&#34;http://web.mit.edu/&#34;&gt;MIT&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.caltech.edu/&#34;&gt;CALTECH&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.case.edu/&#34;&gt;CASE&lt;/a&gt; to name but a few. They seem pretty competent.  Is it possible there&amp;rsquo;s a large vacuum at Chrysler which sucks the smarts out of the engineering staff, followed closely by the moral vacuum which removes all traces of morality.   I have long thought that American ingenuity can solve most problems.  The difficulty is that American greed removes the problem solving substituting marketing glitz, &lt;a href=&#34;http://shakespeare.mit.edu/macbeth/macbeth.5.5.html&#34; title=&#34;Apologies to Shakespeare&#34;&gt;full of sound and fury, signifying, nothing. &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plunder me again</title>
      <link>http://redlinedoc.com/2010/04/plunder-me-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://redlinedoc.com/2010/04/plunder-me-again/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As I read Paul Krugman&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://community.nytimes.com/comments/www.nytimes.com/2010/04/19/opinion/19krugman.html?sort=highlights&amp;amp;offset=1&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Looters in Loafers&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;.i felt a bit prescient having blogged &lt;a href=&#34;lhttp://irv.ourexchange.net/2010/03/bonuses_for_bettors/&#34;&gt;Bonuses for Bettors &lt;/a&gt; before the current revelations. Perhaps that should be re-evaluations. Slippery as eels these folks, they fall back on &amp;hellip; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0413845/&#34;&gt;caveat emptor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;rdquo; although the only non-blinded fellows in the room were they. It was the impending release of poor&lt;a href=&#34;http://abcnews.go.com/Politics/Supreme_Court/enron-ceo-jeffrey-skilling-asks-supreme-court-trial/story?id=9954946&#34;&gt; Jeffrey&lt;/a&gt;, once the smartest guy in the room, realizing there were more cats to be skinned, er I mean folks to be fleeced. Well Jeff felt he got a raw deal and he, unable to wallow in the spoils.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When first I read of the looting and larceny I thought &lt;a href=&#34;http://headsonpikes.blogspot.com/&#34;&gt;&amp;#8216;heads on pikes&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#8216;; but I&amp;rsquo;m not blood thirsty enough for that. Then I watched Lehman implode and the jackals gather at the corpse to pick the sweet meats. Not one of them felt there was any wrong doing. Indeed they were all self righteous. At that time how little we knew.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve generally supported the aims of this administration (nationally), but find myself watching the the internal dealing and the Goldman-Sachs&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sfgate.com/cgi-bin/article.cgi?f=/g/a/2010/04/19/bloomberg1376-L152U61A1I4H-1.DTL&#34;&gt; revolving door spinning &lt;/a&gt;so fast its really a fan. I once saw a special about how an engineering firm kept their government work on one side of the hall and their civilian contracts on the other, claiming a &lt;a href=&#34;http://headsonpikes.blogspot.com/&#34;&gt;mehitza&lt;/a&gt; of sorts so that the engineers, who otherwise ate in the same mess facilities, used the same parking lots and other than sharing separate entryways, were really not at all co-mingled. Right.  When the former &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sfgate.com/cgi-bin/article.cgi?f=/g/a/2010/04/19/bloomberg1376-L152U61A1I4H-1.DTL&#34;&gt;chieftans&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sfgate.com/cgi-bin/article.cgi?f=/g/a/2010/04/19/bloomberg1376-L152U61A1I4H-1.DTL&#34;&gt;Goldman Sachs&lt;/a&gt; run not only the regulating agencies but are also judge and jury I wonder. Hmmm. Right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is not an &amp;#8216;appearance of wrongdoing&amp;rsquo;. It is offal on the table, and it would appear to be us, the American public. Perhaps I should revisit my former thoughts. Heads on pikes seem not so bad&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Again and again</title>
      <link>http://redlinedoc.com/2009/08/again-and-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://redlinedoc.com/2009/08/again-and-again/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Why can&amp;rsquo;t we pay for health care for everyone? Why is it that is this country we have such a divide? Is it our puritanical upbringing which says work hard and you&amp;rsquo;ll get your rewards?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sadly folks, the Puritan&amp;rsquo;s didn&amp;rsquo;t have it all that wonderfully. Life was hard but it was short. There were no antibiotics, no x-rays, no casts, no real surgery (with anesthesia). Hospitals were to be avoided as pest houses and physicians themselves at the time knew they did little for their patients. Some cures were probably worse than the diseases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we have modernized medicine, why can&amp;rsquo;t we modernize the way we provide care for our citizens. Why do we in the land of the brave, home of the free, live with a 3rd world medical care system. Sure people come here. The Sultan of Brunei came here and got wonderful care. M. D., a fictional name, in the north end of Hartford got &lt;a href=&#34;Http://www.urbandictionary.com/define.php?term=turfed&#34;&gt;turfed&lt;/a&gt;. Hmmm. Would the divide and provision of care have to do with money?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indeed it does. The wheels grind exceeding slowly for those with limited funding.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Last you a lifetime!</title>
      <link>http://redlinedoc.com/2009/07/last-you-a-lifetime/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://redlinedoc.com/2009/07/last-you-a-lifetime/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I found myself unaccountably angry at statements from the auto manufacturers the other day. The mouth of Sauron from Chrysler tells us that to save money and jobs (and get a handout from Uncle Sam), that they&amp;rsquo;re dropping several lines, among them the PT Cruiser. Not much new. One of the reasons they&amp;rsquo;re dropping the cruiser is that they put a bad engine in the thing; but it sold. So what!?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what? So I&amp;rsquo;m one of the poor schleps that bought a PT Cruiser but had some misgivings about the power train. I put a lot of miles on a car, somewhere around 36000. I bought their extended warranty because it came with &amp;lsquo;lifetime&amp;rsquo; oil changes. I figured at 30-40$ a clip and I change oil monthly.  Dutifully I took the car in for changes. Once day I heard a horrible racket from the engine. It was the power steering pump, I later found out. My mechanic looked at the car and realized (he called me under the car) to see the broken front motor mount, the torn high-pressure power steering link and the torn oil line. Hmmmm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cars are for me rather like black boxes. These even -=I=- with my untrammeled vision could easily see. The oil had been changed a mere 3 days before!  The dealer never did get back to me. I stopped using the oil change service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The car will last until it dies. I keep it oiled and well fed but I know that time is not on my side. Now that its been orphaned things will only get worse. The fat cats at Chrysler will dine well and sleep without ethics. What saddens me most is that the country I love, the country I fought for, the country I raised my children in is eating itself, or rather being eaten alive by the corporations who made it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was a time when things were built to last. There was always a wink and a smile when some things had built in obsolesence. Where are the buggy whip manufacturers, the boom box makers, the 8 track fabricators .. but things were built with an eye toward building customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My next door neighbor when I was a kid used to tell stories of his dad who ran a general store in Coventry CT. One of the customers (in the late 1800&amp;rsquo;s) came in complaining about the axe he had. &amp;lsquo;Best axe I ever bought&amp;rsquo; said he, &amp;lsquo;six new heads, seven new handles. Last me a lifetime&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moments of madness</title>
      <link>http://redlinedoc.com/2009/07/moments-of-madness/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://redlinedoc.com/2009/07/moments-of-madness/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was driving home this evening listening to the discussion about why the financial institutions are putting out the same hybrid products that brought us this wonderful recession, hearing the pundits explain that it brings capital into the markets and although its a bit (a bit?) risky, these instruments help to drive the market. Ok. I&amp;rsquo;m no financial whiz but didn&amp;rsquo;t we just loan billions and trillions of dollars to these self serving financial institutions to NOT have them bet the store? Wasn&amp;rsquo;t part of the project to make them more fiscally responsible? Somehow we the poor schmoes who pay taxes are subsidizing a very wealthy gambling habit. We&amp;rsquo;re bound to lose. We may be the house but in this case we hold none of the trump cards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trump cards? Isn&amp;rsquo;t this banking? Isn&amp;rsquo;t this where the banker sits across the table and says &amp;ldquo;Well Joe, opening a restaurant is a risky business and we&amp;rsquo;ll need some collateral&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; or so it was in the past. Now we have bankers betting (your house) on 10:1 or 100:1 odds knowing that the worst will be that the government will for a time be paying into their bank. Where are their ethics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ahh ethics. It seems that capitalism trumps ethics. Do undo others before they do unto you. The Ivory Tower at Harvard spoke several weeks ago about plans to include teaching ethics to the business school. Its the piper teaching the cobra. Once the cobra leaves the nest, well then its just a bunch of snakes isn&amp;rsquo;t it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It wasn&amp;rsquo;t until the sentencing the other week that I got it. Bernie Madoff&amp;hellip; made off with our monies. Too sweet. such onomatopoeia. No one saw the deal too good to be true, 30:1 winnings? Get real folks. Its all about the casino, and we the taxpayer have been at the largest gaming table ever, Bernie and his friends (and there are more no doubt) are pikers compared to the banks and so called financial houses that take our monies and throw it on the international craps table. Oh lost a few billion in that scheme. Not to worry Uncle will back you&amp;hellip; .and he has.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heads on pikes</title>
      <link>http://redlinedoc.com/2009/06/heads-on-pikes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://redlinedoc.com/2009/06/heads-on-pikes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It seems its a day of good news bad news. The good news seems to be that the boys at Goldman Sachs are snuffling at the trough and ready to suck up those great well deserved bonuses for having put us in the worst recession since the 30&amp;rsquo;s perhaps worse than that.  I fear that we missed an opportunity for heads on pikes. I&amp;rsquo;m not ordinarily a gory sort of fellow; however, if a few of those egregious folk had their heads up along the boulevard perhaps fewer of these guys would be snorting at the trough so soon. Its a sign that regulation has lost and that we as a nation have or will loose big time now that the game is a foot and the money is liberally flying around again.&lt;br /&gt;
It makes me wonder in some ways what the big call is for CEO&amp;rsquo;s. I hear one company after another looking for the most expensive CEO guy they can find. I have no problem paying for success. Its the paying for the failures. United Airlines, General Motors, Chrysler, Hewlett Packard &amp;ndash; each of those men and women walked away handsomely endowed with bonus and super bonus and stock options. As each of these companies tanked and drew down the economy we threw MORE money at CEO&amp;rsquo;s. I&amp;rsquo;ve yet to see cat skeleton&amp;rsquo;s around full cat food bowls.  I believe if we all went to reasonable executive pay and said NO MORE! that indeed CEO&amp;rsquo;s would be paid proportionately and reasonably. Perhaps we should make the CEO take some of the risk (not with fake-o securities from the board but with his own monies. Perhaps, as in days of yore, CEO&amp;rsquo;s should bear a percentage of risk and win-lose with the company.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Danny DeVito, ever a mirror for the times, did it well with &amp;ldquo;Other People&amp;rsquo;s Money&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Harvard business school recently announced that they might teach business ethics to their grads. What a concept! Such things as stealing from old ladies is wrong, wiping out the life savings of people and towns is poor for future business, and the future. My son said that if once in a while if the inchoate mob, those who lost nearly everything, had an opportunity to be in a closed area with the hedgies and mutualaholics who ground their savings from real to imaginary numbers that much of this would be object lesson.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But then, that&amp;rsquo;s pretty gory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Heads on pikes. Not a lot. Just a few. Some in Wall Street. Some on K Street. Some along the mall. Sobers the crowd and makes us remember that there really are people who are responsible. Until then, it&amp;rsquo;s still &amp;ldquo;Buddy can you spare a (discounted) dime.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>