<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Post-rsses on Redline Doc</title>
    <link>http://redlinedoc.com/post/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Post-rsses on Redline Doc</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://redlinedoc.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Cultural insensitivity</title>
      <link>http://redlinedoc.com/2012/07/cultural-insensitivity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://redlinedoc.com/2012/07/cultural-insensitivity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m glad my culture of&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.commentarymagazine.com/article/shakespeare-shylock-and-the-jews/&#34;&gt; 5700 years&lt;/a&gt; has been reduced to &amp;lsquo;good moneymaking&amp;rsquo;.  After all, I&amp;rsquo;m sure the Moses, as he descended from the mount had a marketing plan to sell little &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.commentarymagazine.com/article/shakespeare-shylock-and-the-jews/&#34;&gt;Torah&lt;/a&gt;s all over, because he was &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/19579910&#34;&gt;culturally attuned&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can hear  the clang of symbols as my &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Passover&#34;&gt;ancestors fled Egypt&lt;/a&gt; making sure they stowed the gold on their way out of the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Throughout the centuries&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.adl.org/Anti_semitism/jewsandmoney/default.asp&#34;&gt; Jews have been derided for their attentiveness to money&lt;/a&gt; and things money, often imbued with powers never given them to control monies.  &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.commentarymagazine.com/article/shakespeare-shylock-and-the-jews/&#34;&gt;Shylock&lt;/a&gt;, that most derided of Shakesperian characters is but one of many.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr Romney, do you not hear the &lt;a href=&#34;http://patrickmacmanus.wordpress.com/2011/03/13/from-gaza-listening-to-the-hoof-beats-of-history/&#34;&gt;hoofbeats of history&lt;/a&gt;?    When you suggest that the Jewish people culturally are attuned to moneymaking did you disconnect from our recent history?  The&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.calvin.edu/academic/cas/gpa/images/sturmer/sturm05.jpg&#34;&gt; images of Jews and money&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://emperors-clothes.com/antisem/naz-sov.htm&#34;&gt;world domination&lt;/a&gt; flooded German newspapers, particularly &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.calvin.edu/academic/cas/gpa/images/sturmer/ds37-47.jpg&#34; title=&#34;Racist papers of the 1930&#39;s &#34;&gt;de Sturmer&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I understand the rush for votes.  I also understand that history is less forgiving than we thought. Apparently we are slow to learn those lessons. &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikiquote.org/wiki/George_Santayana&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Those who cannot remember the past, are condemned to repeat it.&amp;ldquo; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scammed again!</title>
      <link>http://redlinedoc.com/2012/03/scammed-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://redlinedoc.com/2012/03/scammed-again/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently I sought to upgrade from my &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.att.com/dsl&#34;&gt;DSL service &lt;/a&gt;which we&amp;rsquo;ve had since 1998 or thereabouts, finding that the current (supposedly) &lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;728&lt;/sub&gt; was really &lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;284&lt;/sub&gt; on a recent billing. Its not easy upgrading.  Since we took &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slate.com/articles/news_and_politics/jurisprudence/2007/01/bellwether.html&#34;&gt;M aBell&lt;/a&gt; (you do remember the good old &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wPYN1nk-fIA&#34; title=&#34;from: The President&#39;s Analyst&#34;&gt;AT&amp;amp;T &lt;/a&gt;?) and made it many pieces.  Its rather like the &lt;a href=&#34;http://rogerebert.suntimes.com/apps/pbcs.dll/article?AID=/19990806/REVIEWS/908060303&#34;&gt;Iron Giant&lt;/a&gt;, who reassembles himself from the blown apart pieces. He, on the other had is for good.  This, more like the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=do0x-Egc6oA&#34;&gt;evil empire&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adventurous and with some time, I call the service part of my current DSL provider only to be lost in an automated system that once in, is difficult to escape, or in my case, so insistent on one course that I could not re-enter the system.  Desperate, I decided to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sing365.com/music/lyric.nsf/lie-lie-lie-lyrics-system-of-a-down/4861f147eeb08f0848257384002b1fc4&#34;&gt;lie to the system&lt;/a&gt; and it immediately sent me to a human.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I fared not much better since the human could not understand why I wasn&amp;rsquo;t happy and didn&amp;rsquo;t want all the &lt;a href=&#34;http://idioms.thefreedictionary.com/bells+and+whistles&#34;&gt;bells and whistles&lt;/a&gt; services they were offering . It&amp;rsquo;s rather like getting a car, you want wheels , doors and some amenities; they want to sell you upgraded chrome or something the size of a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fprado.com/armorsite/abrams.htm&#34;&gt;Abrams M1 tank&lt;/a&gt;.  Sometimes I feel like a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.com/imgres?start=188&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;biw=1280&amp;amp;bih=909&amp;amp;tbm=isch&amp;amp;prmd=imvns&amp;amp;tbnid=QNz16RTNldQ1LM:&amp;amp;imgrefurl=http://sykeswrites.wordpress.com/category/fresh-fare/play/&amp;amp;docid=tvYCVF3kv3tXPM&amp;amp;imgurl=http://sykeswrites.files.wordpress.com/2010/04/tracks01.jpg%253Fw%253D470&amp;amp;w=424&amp;amp;h=283&amp;amp;ei=QqZPT6qgNMbY0QH0xLzwDQ&amp;amp;zoom=1&#34;&gt;train on a parallel track or parallel universe&lt;/a&gt; and no matter what, I can&amp;rsquo;t jump from one to the other; but, I digress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, the fourth human says you need U-verse service. Oh? I do?.  She explained to me how much faster all this would be.  She also thought this was FTTP (Fiber to the premises) when I asked several times.  My location is about 550 yards from the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thecentraloffice.com/&#34;&gt;Central Office (CO)&lt;/a&gt; although she said that didn&amp;rsquo;t matter any more. I set an appointment, rubbing my hands anticipating &lt;sup&gt;18&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt; (or maybe better!!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The technician arrived.  He said he had to do some testing and so would DISCONNECT the service which was currently running, and I might add never to reappear again.  He came back several minutes later, all the services phone and internet down, announcing they&amp;rsquo;d have to get another (different truck different division) out there, sometime.  I&amp;rsquo;m glad he didn&amp;rsquo;t use the word soon.  I had a family member at the house who also happens to be very technically able and works in the server maintenance field; not unknowledgeable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gone. Truck, driver, service and when I called they said the installation was &amp;lsquo;in progress&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t. They have an 1830 call rollover in this division. Next day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I call. They still insist this is being fixed and they have to wait for the incoming ticket.  How, by the way do I like my service.  ????  Ok.  I can take a joke.  I wait a few hours. Each of the meat shields the company has put in my way of getting to a person of knowledge says &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m really sorry your&amp;rsquo;re having this trouble&amp;rdquo; but has no helpful actions available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tick tock. We&amp;rsquo;re coming up on a weekend when nothing will get done.  I call in vain hope that a human may be able to hook something up.   The phones are back on line mysteriously.   The human who finally helps says they&amp;rsquo;re really sorry and they&amp;rsquo;ll put it all together on Saturday Morning.  The set up guys are really nice, telling us to call support for the IP addresses and ranges for the static IP&amp;rsquo;s which we&amp;rsquo;ve had these last 14 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m on and off the phone.  The support line tells me that they don&amp;rsquo;t have that I need to call &lt;a href=&#34;https://buy-connectech.att.com/ctcomm/home/index.jsp&#34; title=&#34;Scam Central&#34;&gt;ATT ConnectTech&lt;/a&gt;.   I call.  The scam begins.  You can sign up for one time 5 day service for 149$ or 15$/month 12 month minimum billed to a credit card.  Sorry, we&amp;rsquo;re not part of that phone company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;News to me!  I &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.phrases.org.uk/meanings/pony-up.html&#34;&gt;pony up&lt;/a&gt;, figuring I&amp;rsquo;ll be able to access my system.  No. No. No. Not at all. The Level 2 tech, who is very nice gives me a netmask for a Category C netblock (wow, category C, I don&amp;rsquo;t think that IBM has a cat C netmask) .. but wow, ok.  I might add, not only is it wrong, but it also, of course, doesn&amp;rsquo;t work. The IP and netmask addresses, close but not right either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m tired, angry, frustrated and feel very much taken. AT&amp;amp;T has made my life hellish without much work on their part.   I try, again the U-verse support. This time I get a &lt;a href=&#34;http://cio.ittoolbox.com/groups/strategy-planning/it-workforce-management-sp/standards-for-level-1-2-and-3-support-2862755&#34;&gt;Level 1 support&lt;/a&gt; who says, oh .. you need Level 2.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The information is supplied. &lt;a href=&#34;http://witchstead.wordpress.com/2010/05/26/dawn-breaks-over-marblehea/&#34;&gt;Dawn breaks over the computer.&lt;/a&gt;  I&amp;rsquo;ve been &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.psychologytoday.com/collections/201111/scammed/dont-get-ripped&#34;&gt;scammed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://getsatisfaction.com/att/topics/scammed_by_at_t_u_verse_contract_salesman_then_by_at_t&#34;&gt;by AT&amp;amp;T&lt;/a&gt; yet again.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sin service</title>
      <link>http://redlinedoc.com/2012/01/sin-service/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://redlinedoc.com/2012/01/sin-service/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m astounded at what passes for &lt;a href=&#34;http://oxforddictionaries.com/definition/service?q=service&#34;&gt;service&lt;/a&gt;. I probably shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently I went to a&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bestbuy.com&#34;&gt; BestBuy.&lt;/a&gt;  They employ college grads, young folk, with slicked hair and &amp;lsquo;tude.  I&amp;rsquo;m usually in there, an older guy, tie, shirt looking about for what I need. At first I thought &amp;ldquo;bad clothing&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;bad BO&amp;rdquo; but that&amp;rsquo;s not it.  You can be systematically ignored in the store.  Asking a tech question may or may not get you a human to help, but for me it has worked to the extreme opposite, sent to some corner of the store so that when I get back, that person is gone and another in his/her place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have some news for BestBuy and their ilk. Of the monies we spent on tech this past year, and we spent a fair amount, we spent less than 5% at BestBuy, maybe less this year. These guys are circling to be the next &lt;a href=&#34;http://news.cnet.com/8301-10784_3-9831235-7.html&#34;&gt;CompUSA&lt;/a&gt;. The CompUSA  dudes had it down though.  Customer and service never made it on the same line with them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I watch the no-eye-contact cashiers, the smiles from the managers as they pull the goods through the turnstiles but neglect the customers paying for them,  they fail to understand that it is not employers who pay the wages, they only handle the money. It is the customer who pays the wages (Henry Ford).  They too are doomed, dinosaurs of a different age.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wonder how in this economic&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cjr.org/the_audit/the_race_to_the_bottom.php?page=all&#34;&gt; race to the bottom&lt;/a&gt;, rather than increase the service, turn on the warmth, bring the people in the doors, the assumption that build-it-they-will-come still prevails. I am fortunate but have become much more picky about disbursing my funds, preferring service and knowledge over glitz and push.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its a lesson the car industry has yet to learn as well.  Chrysler, famed for its CEO statement of yore &amp;ldquo;well we don&amp;rsquo;t make that model anymore&amp;rdquo; as an apologia for lousy engineering and a corporate culture of not caring. &lt;a href=&#34;http://hotair.com/archives/2011/05/27/the-fake-chrysler-loan-payoff/&#34;&gt;Bellied up to the National Soup Kitchen&lt;/a&gt; they took the money to renew themselves but if &amp;ldquo;bring back the Dart&amp;rdquo; is any measure of what that means, we&amp;rsquo;re in for more of failed engineering (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2010/07/09/chryslers-pt-cruiser-symb_n_641383.html&#34;&gt;the PT Cruiser&lt;/a&gt;), harum-scarum tactics (most of the&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wired.com/autopia/2009/04/the-new-j8-mils/&#34;&gt; SUV&amp;rsquo;&lt;/a&gt;s), and less attention to the consumer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure advertisement can push the consumer into believing that &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.evsroll.com/Car_pollution_facts.html&#34;&gt;more pollution is better,&lt;/a&gt;  that higher standards (be cautious of that word) would make the industry unprofitable and that what we need is a return to the over-sized, overpriced, under-engineered cars of the 90&amp;rsquo;s or 70&amp;rsquo;s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Service at its worst is at the front lines of restaurants. Somehow, the &amp;lsquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.npr.org/blogs/money/2011/06/24/137346289/why-we-tip&#34;&gt;tip&amp;rsquo;  &lt;/a&gt;has become part of the expected payment, even for non-existent service.  I mean, how much service or even humanity do you get at the local donut parlor?  Mindless avatars push out coffee and what passes for food without ever making eye contact.  And there it is, the tip mug. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t say &amp;lsquo;por service&amp;rsquo; anymore, heaven forfend, just TIP MUG.   I&amp;rsquo;d rather tip the machine at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theautomat.net/&#34;&gt;Horn and Hardart&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Out for breakfast recently we waited as other&amp;rsquo;s were menu&amp;rsquo;d, coffee&amp;rsquo;d then served then left!  I thought wow, we much be invisible. I snagged one of the waitstaff who said, oh excuse me then disappeared, forever. Another came over with coffee offering to get out check. We almost left the restaurant. I demurred and said we&amp;rsquo;d had neither coffee nor menus nor food yet!  Oh my gosh. And she too disappeared. The third came over without eye contact, without &amp;lsquo;gee I&amp;rsquo;m sorry&amp;rsquo; and took the order.  Coffee appeared similarly. The food was delivered but without a rehash or recall. Who knew we wanted a bit of a warm up. Customarily I&amp;rsquo;m a very good tipper but rose to this occasion to tell the person at the register, quietly, what had happened.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We get a lot of that around here&amp;rdquo;, she  said ruefully.  Dinosaurs. I can hear them falling all over the place.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pish tosh</title>
      <link>http://redlinedoc.com/2011/06/pish-tosh/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://redlinedoc.com/2011/06/pish-tosh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ahh my faith in the society of &lt;a href=&#34;http://washingtonexaminer.com/politics/2011/06/obama-rubs-elbows-regulatory-robber-barons&#34;&gt;robber barons &lt;/a&gt;is renewed! On the news: A fine of 156 million is levied for stealing. No jail. No restrictions just the fine at 1% of last years net.  Wow! The cost of doing business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not dismayed anymore. I&amp;rsquo;m sad. I&amp;rsquo;m sure I&amp;rsquo;m not alone. The &lt;a href=&#34;http://moneyland.time.com/2011/06/21/banks-are-hurting-its-all-relative/&#34;&gt;weasels are in the hen house &lt;/a&gt;and have eaten all the chickens and wonder why there are no eggs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More interesting than the fine is the underlying lie. The company, and apparently the big five are all involved, took money from investors, short sold the investment (this means they bet AGAINST the investor making money), told them how wonderful the packaged securities were and then laughed at them for their folly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ho Humm. Business lying as usual. Whats the news here?  We&amp;rsquo;ve suspected for some time that the SEC (Securities and Exchange Commission) was bought and paid for, but now having raped the American economy and managing to blame the poor outcome on the suckers who &lt;a href=&#34;http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;amp;ct2=us%2F0_0_s_4_0_t&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNFF0GqujJNgintdcZqpWnbTFom7HQ&amp;amp;did=e7413863b8afb6a0&amp;amp;cid=8797715370661&amp;amp;ei=zP8BTuj3LoX8ggfA98DtAg&amp;amp;rt=SEARCH&amp;amp;vm=STANDARD&amp;amp;url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.bloomberg.com%2Fnews%2F2011-06-21%2Fgensler-evolving-in-derivatives-war-sees-no-deed-go-unpunished.html&#34;&gt;bought into their racetrack scheme&lt;/a&gt;, the government fails to even slow down this juggernaut.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I agree with comedian &lt;a href=&#34;http://lewisblack.com/bio.aspx&#34;&gt;Lewis Black&lt;/a&gt; who said &amp;ldquo;You should expect of your leaders what you expect of an experienced canoe guide.  We&amp;rsquo;re going down that fork in the river and not the other because down there there&amp;rsquo;s a *#$(* waterfall!!&amp;rdquo;  What we have are disneyesque leaders pushing us &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.snopes.com/disney/films/lemmings.asp&#34;&gt;off the cliff like lemmings&lt;/a&gt;, to make a &amp;#8216;good show&amp;rsquo;.  We should preserve the banks because they&amp;rsquo;re our salvation. HAH.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I watch, from the poorest census district in the United States, not 40 miles from nearly the richest, with the realization that we have always blamed the poor for our outcomes. They&amp;rsquo;re the ones who did this. They created the financial collapse, not the liars at the banks, not the conniving realtors who sold properties they knew would never be repaid, nor the investment banks which rolled all this compost into securities, laughing at the unicorns and morons that would buy such stuff that they themselves had bet against! Imagine that.  An so they have left a trail of devastation and destruction that will take years, if ever to recover from. The folks, trusting their employers to look after them had very low social security payouts but good supplemental income from investments made by their employers  &amp;ndash;  now all vanished at the racetracks of the banking world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.quoteworld.org/quotes/3649&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;It was the best of times, it was the worst of times; it ws the age of wisdom, it was the age of foolishness; it was the epoch of belief, it was the epoch of incredulity; it was the season of Light, it was the season of Darkness; it was the spring of hope, it was the winter of despair; we had everything before us, we had nothing before us; we were all going directly to Heaven, we were all going the other way.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; I&amp;rsquo;d hope there would be some public outcry, anger at the blood in the streets. How Dickensian this has all become.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sucking the marrow</title>
      <link>http://redlinedoc.com/2011/06/sucking-the-marrow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://redlinedoc.com/2011/06/sucking-the-marrow/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I work in a Community Health Center and as such we see the folks at the bottom of the health ladder, well more like health string these days.  It must be that time for the HMO&amp;rsquo;s to come suck the marrow out of the bones of the state insured patients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How so, you ask?  We, the physicians, are flooded with requests to change medications. Change? Well yes.  We need to use cheaper, not necessarily better for the patient, drugs for the patient to keep up our end of the deal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Deal?  Well yes.  It would be inconceivable that we, the physicians, would not wish to enhance the fortunes of the struggling pharma boys (and girls  &amp;ndash;  to be PC).    By &amp;rsquo;re aligning&amp;rsquo; these medications, we can save, well a fortune (not for you buddy !!) for the struggling and underdog HMO&amp;rsquo;s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each year its the same, although the names change to keep the corporate profits spread like marmalade across companies. We get letters to inform (me) that some poor schlep of a patient has been provided with a transitional supply of prescription X while I go to look up a cheaper chicken.  The instructions are voluminous and there is room for exception.  Exceptions of course need be filed with the proper authority no doubt in some basement with missing stairs kept in the file cabinet guarded by a jaguar, though they&amp;rsquo;d like us to think that this process is made for &amp;lsquo;helping&amp;rsquo; the patient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is an implication within all this, a copy which has, of course, been forwarded to the patient, that the profligate doctor (that would be me) has wantonly wasted the monies of the HMO.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nowhere does it say that this is being done to save monies for some of the richest greediest corporations on earth.  Nowhere does it imply that these monies saved will go to their bottom lines.   In many ways this IS the koan of capitalism: make the little guy work so the big guy gets bigger and maybe some of this goodness, probably not money, will rain down on you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So much for the marrow. What will they suck next.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A View From Xela. Implementing FreeMED in Guatemala.</title>
      <link>http://redlinedoc.com/2010/10/a-view-from-xela-implementing-freemed-in-guatemala/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://redlinedoc.com/2010/10/a-view-from-xela-implementing-freemed-in-guatemala/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://jbuchbinder.com&#34;&gt;Jeff&lt;/a&gt; and I undertook implementation of &lt;a href=&#34;http://freemedsoftware.org/org/&#34;&gt;FreeMED&lt;/a&gt; an Open Source Electronic Medical Record and practice management system for the &lt;a href=&#34;http://popwujclinic.org/&#34;&gt;Pop-Wuj Clinic&lt;/a&gt;, a primary care, non-profit, free and open clinic in &lt;a href=&#34;http://maps.google.com/maps?f=q&amp;amp;source=s_q&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;q=&amp;amp;vps=5&amp;amp;jsv=282d&amp;amp;sll=37.020098,-95.625&amp;amp;sspn=91.574054,158.027344&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;geocode=Fbxh4gAdWXyL-g&amp;amp;split=0&#34;&gt;Quezeltenango&lt;/a&gt;, Guatemala. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;&amp;quot;http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3149/2907922953_b0f9bf5e0f_d.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;A view of Santa Maria from a quiet street&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The clinic, founded by members of Pop-Wuj Spanish School, (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pop-wuj.org/&#34;&gt;http://www.pop-wuj.org/&lt;/a&gt;)  a non-profit school for teaching Spanish language, and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.weillcornell.org/physician/jstgeorge/index.html&#34;&gt;Dr. Jonathan St. George&lt;/a&gt;, an emergency department physician at Weill Cornell Medical Center . Dr St. George began with a space and a concept and has with coordination with the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.timmyfoundation.org/&#34;&gt;Timmy Foundation&lt;/a&gt; staffed a regular clinic with a full time physician and assistants, recruited a part time dentist and a part time community physician to work in the clinic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3027/2559182101_022b949107_d.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Pop Wuj Clinic on the street&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Students of medicine or allied fields attending Pop-Wuj Spanish Language school assist with chores and triage at the clinic in the morning and then attend their language classes in the afternoon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is planned for the clinic to be self sustaining.  To derive funds, we will offer continuing medical education courses in Travel and International Medicine. the staff, all volunteer, will make the courses available, and the fees used to fund the clinic and operations.  We plan to use Open Source Training tools as a basis for online and study courses both for Pop-Wuj school and for Access Medicine, the teaching wing.  We hope to prove this funding model within three years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The installation of &lt;strong&gt;FreeMED&lt;/strong&gt; was not without its problems. Servers donated by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sgi.com&#34;&gt;SGI/Rackable Systems &lt;/a&gt; complemented laptops donated by Jeff&amp;#8217;s employer helped get us off the ground. Immediate problems with infrastructure, the system wasn&amp;#8217;t at all grounded coupled with a need for stable power, necessitated the purchase of a UPS to protect the servers.  Difficulty with the structures which are of concrete and re-bar hindered good WIFI transmissions within the building. We capitulated and wired the building for CAT5 (ish). I say “ish”, because the local wire is probably CAT3 maybe. We didn&amp;#8217;t have any interference problems that we could pick up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once hooked up, we split the system for registration, triage, physicians and pharmacy. Registration has been by hand and is transiting well to the electronic system. The intake person has good aptitude with computers and was a quick study with some help. Triage, which is really vital signs and complaint are done by visiting medical students. An immediate difficulty is that the person in this position changes sometimes several times during clinic hours. There is very little regularity and registering each of these people will create some problems. At the moment, we&amp;#8217;re continuing to register each person in the system and privilege them as such. The suggestion, by some, that we create a group without name, is problematic from several standpoints.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Physician training was minimal because of initial delays in deploying the system. However, I spent time with the physicians and we have enabled remote secure access so that they can use and manoeuvre through the system. For the most part, physicians are not the stumbling block.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a large pharmacy and much of the medication for patients is dispensed from this bank of medications. We did not pre-enter the medications and are still working ways to get some handle on the bulk of and entry of these medications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4108/5016001755_048865f4ca_z_d.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;At the Solola outreach&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4125/5016646688_31a230ceef_d.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Solola Clinic&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4151/5016042105_cee7515d92_d.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Solola Clinic&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4154/5016057385_895a710e3d_z_d.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Dentistry in the Pueblos&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The dental portion of &lt;strong&gt;FreeMED&lt;/strong&gt; will be implemented once the medical is stable and in use. &lt;strong&gt;FreeMED&lt;/strong&gt; continues to evolve. There were some specific changes made to accommodate the needs of this clinic and its staff. We hope to have some hard statistics from the program by mid year with full integration of the old (paper) medical records. The &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fujitsu.com&#34;&gt;Fujitsu corporation&lt;/a&gt; has donated scanners which will enable us to port paper records into the system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once we have fully implemented &lt;strong&gt;FreeMED&lt;/strong&gt; in the clinic, we hope to add Android capability to the Xela system, allowing for remote access as well as telemedicine conferencing.  The Android capability, already built into &lt;strong&gt;FreeMED&lt;/strong&gt; permits recording and transcribing of teleconferences directly to the medical record. Other Android features are planned. &lt;strong&gt;FreeMED&lt;/strong&gt; does work seamlessly to provide access by Android to appointment and other portions of the system including the internal messaging system.  There are other anticipated donations of medical equipment including monitors to the clinic. Those too are planned to be integrated using the SHIM portion of &lt;strong&gt;FreeMED.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FreeMED&lt;/strong&gt; is an opensource GPL-licensed product, in use worldwide. &lt;strong&gt;FreeMED&lt;/strong&gt; recently announced the release of the 0.9.0 beta version. More information is available through the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.freemedsoftware.org&#34;&gt;FreeMED website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in helping with the clinic either by donation of time, energy,  equipment or monies, please contact donations at popwujclinic dot org    Another trip to the clinic is planned for May. If you have an interest in international or travel medicine and wish to contribute by taking the offered courses and /or &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.popwujclinic.org/&#34;&gt;contribute expertise contact&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>REAL Health care -- in the trenches.</title>
      <link>http://redlinedoc.com/2010/10/real-health-care-in-the-trenches/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://redlinedoc.com/2010/10/real-health-care-in-the-trenches/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I read Paul Romer&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://healthcareitstrategy.com/2010/10/12/the-effect-of-healthcare-reform-on-others-2/&#34;&gt;The effect of Health Care Reform&lt;/a&gt; on others, a play on the vagaries of our dysfunctional healthcare system and putative illnesses of &lt;a href=&#34;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mother_Goose&#34;&gt;Mother Goose&lt;/a&gt; characters.  I admit it (a guilty pleasure) I laughed. Then I reflected on the daily life in our&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.chshartford.org&#34;&gt; Community Health Center,&lt;/a&gt; in Connecticut, located in poorest city of its size in the nation. The irony is just too much. We &lt;a href=&#34;http://wiki.answers.com/Q/Why_is_connecticut_call_the_nutmeg_state&#34;&gt;(nutmegers)&lt;/a&gt; are the wealthiest per captita state in the nation!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But- I digress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A patient appears at our primary care clinic on Friday. Classic signs of cholecystitis (gall bladder attack).  We hustle her by transport to the emergency room. Monday morning she&amp;rsquo;s BACK!  At the emergency room, the nice physician gave her the name of several surgeons she could call to have her gall bladder fixed. None take her insurance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An 82 year old lady lives in her car. Bernie (this is too good) Madeoff with the retirement funding. She can&amp;rsquo;t afford the taxes. She lives in her car.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A patient comes for diabetic medication, gets a glucometer (to measure the sugar), strips (to use in the machine) but the company doesn&amp;rsquo;t pay for the lancets to draw the blood from the finger. Urmmmmmm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A patient drops a heavy object on her foot. She goes (of course) to the emergency room, diagnosed with a fracture but referred to the clinic so that she can have a cast put on.  She is uninsured.   I might add this over a five day period.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A patient comes with a kidney infection. No problem. Antibiotics. Oh  &amp;ndash;  we don&amp;rsquo;t cover THAT antibiotic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A patient, finally stabilized on psychiatric medication shows up for a refill. UhOh. You need a prior authorization. What? This patient has  been taking this for a year. No matter. We need to consider the forms (they say) to make sure the patient is getting the best medication. Insurance oversight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A letter arrived the other day from one of the major drug companies letting us know that they are going to be direct advertising to consumers for certain drugs so that they (the consumers) will know what best to ask for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A young boy comes having (as children are wont to do) leaped off a picnic table and stepped on some glass. The local ER (no problem) sees the child, recognizes that there is glass &amp;lsquo;somewhere&amp;rsquo; in the wound, sews up the wound, and sends the parents off in search of a surgeon who will see them on state insurance. Two days later. They arrive at our clinic looking for guidance. We are fortunate to have some favors to call in. He gets care.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lest you think out there that is is a factor of my particular city, its not. As I speak with colleagues around the country, this is the rule not the exception. As insurers tighten the profit noose, looking to their bottom lines not yours, this is a frightening and every more common occurrence. As hospital emergency room expenses rise the quest to slide more care out to the community increases. Its shoddy. Its terrible. Its not good medicine, hell its not good care in the third world. It is however our current system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Healthcare reform may change some of this but we are only at a beginning. I praise Paul for bringing a bit of humour to what is, for me, a very black, dark sad subject.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>it couldn&#39;t hurt .. or could it</title>
      <link>http://redlinedoc.com/2010/10/it-couldnt-hurt-or-could-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://redlinedoc.com/2010/10/it-couldnt-hurt-or-could-it/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been watching with interest the current Republican party dance around repeal of the Healthcare insurance legislation just passed.  Its a sad bit of badly made political salad with very little for those who need health insurance, a guaranteed business for the insurance companies (universal sign up), &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slate.com/id/2224621/&#34; title=&#34;Big Pharma Billy Tauzin&#34;&gt;guaranteed pharma profits (no pharma negotiation) &lt;/a&gt;and extension of the market for about 40% of those who are still uncovered or uninsured.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;State legislatures, not to be overlooked are trying their best to carve themselves in our out of the new Heatlhcare bill by blocking advances or by shouting states rights.  With hard economic times, its easy to get voters to hear the shouting but miss the salient points.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve missed the boat, again. Smoke and mirrors and distraction reign supreme. The emperor, or his bill, have no clothes. This does not cover a majority of the uninsured. I&amp;rsquo;m waiting to see how those who are unemployed, now some approaching the 2 year mark, will pay for this bit of fluff.  The state&amp;rsquo;s assistance systems were already at a foundering point and shoving the burden to physicians and hospitals for the under and uninsured will only exacerbate the problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a bit of shuck and drag going on here. We&amp;rsquo;re told that we need to work to pass this. We&amp;rsquo;re told it will bankrupt us. We&amp;rsquo;re told this is socialism at its worst.  Socialism?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today one of the walking wounded comes to the clinic. She works 40-50 hours a week, full time  she&amp;rsquo;s told, at one of the local hospitals. To expedite services the hospital contracts out its housekeeping. The firm, to keep profits ripe,  they don&amp;rsquo;t pay insurance.  Hmm. Ok. We took what was a paid in-house position, took away the benefits, hired the same folks to do the same job so that the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=p220yi2VOj8&#34; title=&#34;I was gonna  be an engineer &#34;&gt;profits would stay as high as maybe &lt;/a&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I digress. Here&amp;rsquo;s a full time working person with no insurance.  How is a public option for her, socialism?  From where I sit, we pay into the medicare system.  We pay it in wages and taxes and reap a long term benefit devoid of the need for stockholders to benefit. Although an inconstant fiduciary, generally governments have handled trust funds much better than banks or insurance companies, always looking to the next gaming table, ripening the profits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we allow the loud shouts to take back the minimal advances, and I agree its far from perfect, we&amp;rsquo;ll end up with still more uninsured.  The hidden cost of the &amp;lsquo;uninsured&amp;rsquo; long patched over by draining high end payments from private insurers into the unbalanced pot is at an end. The insurance blokes, have cut off that avenue. The uninsured now go to emergency rooms, expensive care, and not much of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Emphasis from the Healthcare Plan was on primary care, extending to patients the ability to see and to find competent expert medical care. If we persist at deconstructing the fragile imperfect house, we&amp;rsquo;ll have but a very expensive house of cards fallen loosely and very expensively apart.  Threats of Medicare cuts are more thunder than substance. We do need government to help us. Watch carefully.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Xela and more on the 19th</title>
      <link>http://redlinedoc.com/2010/09/xela-and-more-on-the-19th/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://redlinedoc.com/2010/09/xela-and-more-on-the-19th/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hola!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have arrived.  The medical brigade to Pop-Wuj has landed. We arrived on different flights but managed to coordinate being in the same part of the air terminal.  Customs went very smoothly although one of the bags with the primary server didn&amp;rsquo;t make it; it will be found an delivered soon (probably a mix up at Miami-Dade airport).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Out goal. Set up &lt;a href=&#34;http://freemedsoftware.org&#34; title=&#34;FreeMED, Open Source Medical Record &#34;&gt;FreeMED&lt;/a&gt; for use in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://popwujaccess.org&#34; title=&#34;Pop-Wuj Medical Clinic &#34;&gt;Pop-Wuj&lt;/a&gt; Clinic.  The crew this week is here to work the medical clinic, assist Dr. Meg Sullivan, the clinic director and install and fire test FreeMED as well as transfer as much of the medical records as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our bus met us at the airport and quickly loaded the crew and luggage. Its a four plus hour trip from &lt;a href=&#34;http://maps.google.com/maps?f=q&amp;amp;source=s_q&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;q=&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;geocode=FVX73gAdkoqa-g&amp;amp;split=0&#34;&gt;Guatemala City&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;http://maps.google.com/maps?f=q&amp;amp;source=s_q&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;q=&amp;amp;vps=1&amp;amp;jsv=277b&amp;amp;sll=14.613817,-90.532837&amp;amp;sspn=0.069931,0.111322&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;geocode=FfG24QAdcoqI-g&amp;amp;split=0&#34;&gt;Quetzeltenango&lt;/a&gt;, more often referred to by its &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/K&#39;iche&#39;_language&#34; title=&#34;Quiche&#34;&gt;K&amp;rsquo;iche&amp;rsquo;  or Quiche&lt;/a&gt; name, &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Quetzaltenango&#34; title=&#34;Xela&#34;&gt;Xela&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many of you may have read of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-latin-america-11208807&#34; title=&#34;Guatemalan Mudslides&#34;&gt;mudslides in the Guatemalan Highlands&lt;/a&gt;. The roads show evidence of the slides with many washouts of the roadway.   There were active drops with the busdriver, doing his usual Monte Carlo style driving weaving in and out of one way and two way highway areas on CA1-WEST.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We stopped to eat lunch along the way at a small restaurant nestled in the highlands. There I have my first coordinated pictures of the the team, minus me at this point. The lunch was a variety of foods common in the region, a bit more that we would normally have done for an interim meal, but satisfying.  Back on the bus for the last 2 &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;  hours into Xela we arrived about 6pm local time.  Most of us are at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.comeseeit.com/&#34;&gt;Casa Manen&lt;/a&gt;, a local bed and breakfast.  &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/profile.php?id=9025787&#34;&gt;Shelley&lt;/a&gt; chose, as I will next week, to live with a Spanish family.  We dropped Shelley at Pop-Wuj and will rejoin with her in the morning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because of the two hour time shift to Guatemalan time, although we&amp;rsquo;re all a bit wasted from the trip and the planes and leaving New York at 4AM its only 8 local time.  The crew goes to a local restaurant over looking the Plaza for some sit down and group building.   We&amp;rsquo;re all pretty revved about the morning and the week to come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bed time, well room time about 10pm in Xela.  These blogs will be about 1 day off because of the local time changes, but I hope to have more pictures and more local interest shortly.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shelley Runs Demi Marathon</title>
      <link>http://redlinedoc.com/2010/09/shelley-runs-demi-marathon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://redlinedoc.com/2010/09/shelley-runs-demi-marathon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I don´t have pictures yet but Shelley ran with John Sullivan in a (billed as 26 km) race through the streets of &lt;a href=&#34;es.wikipedia.org/wiki/Quetzaltenango&#34;&gt;Xela&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The race began a bit late and Dr. Sullivan and I were watching on street corners for the racers.  Its 2600 meteres up here so the air is thin.  Things done Guatemaltecan style are often without much preparation. There were no crossing guards, no blockoff´s to run interference for the &lt;a href=&#34;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chicken_bus&#34;&gt;Chicken Bus&lt;/a&gt; population and the cars seemed relatively oblivous of the racers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hills were daunting. The traffic next to the runners spewed dark deisel fumes as the racers coughed and ran.  Motorcycles, always taking the smaller parts of the road roared by .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were able to watch the race from four vantage points  &amp;ndash;  the last so close to the finish line that  I didn´t get to photograph Shelley at the finish.  She insists that the race was only a 15k but she finished and she and John were sore but happy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pictures I hope later and a short video as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Signing off for a bit until I can get to pictures and uploads.   Do check out my Flickr page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hola&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Xela and the clinic  the 21st</title>
      <link>http://redlinedoc.com/2010/09/xela-and-the-clinic-the-21st/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://redlinedoc.com/2010/09/xela-and-the-clinic-the-21st/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sorry for the long delay out there but there have  been some connection problems as well as difficulties uploading photos to FLICKR so that they won&amp;rsquo;t take up all the room in the world.  Tuesday was clinic day at Pop-Wuj in the city.  The line up for clinic is not unlike that at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.chshartford.og&#34;&gt;CHS.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a clinician I tail around one of the local doctors, Dr. Christian.  He works Tuesday, Wednesday and Thursday&amp;rsquo;s at the clinic and does a small wound clinic on Tuesday and Friday mornings.  Although there are many out-clinics, helping in the pueblos, the clinic here is run regularly and the out clinics when there are volunteers or students to help with managing the &amp;lsquo;stuff&amp;rsquo; of setting up a clinic away from a home base.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most surprising and yet elemental thing for me is the similarity of the patients here and at home.  Our first wound care was an ulcer caused by a hot water burn. She has a fluid load and some swelling as well as some mild but growing venous stasis.  Wound care here is much the same, debridement, support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our next, came without her support hose&lt;span&gt;.  &amp;rdquo;I left them at home today&amp;rdquo;, she said. When challenged about wearing the stockings regularly &amp;#8211; she doesn&amp;rsquo;t. They itch in the late day when the sun is up and out. I gave her a strategy to wear them only in the morning.  She laughs, the way my patients in the states do.  Dr. Christian and I exchange a knowing glance. She might.  She gives us both kisses and warm handshakes.  Its all the same. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More patients. There are a lot of musculoskeletal complaints here. People use their bodies as handcarts. From the women who cary 20-30kg loads on their heads to the men who carry 100kg sacks of dirt or stone or concrete on their backs using a headband, the difficulties are related to a harsh life here. None of that is evidenced in the clinic &amp;#8211; they are all grateful to have care. No one pushes. No one shoves. There are children everywhere and most of them a bit bashful.  Being nearly &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; taller than most I look rather giant to most of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The line trickles in and in two rooms with some seen on the cuff, we see 63 patients in about 5 hours. The care? First rate given some of the limitations.  There is no EKG.  Blood pressure monitoring is done in a clinic where you can scarcely hear yourself let alone small variations in sound. Medicine is, for the most part donated and solves many of the problems.  There isn&amp;rsquo;t much polypharmacy here. Even older folks walk nearly everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are trying to install &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.freemedsoftware.org&#34;&gt;FreeMED&lt;/a&gt; but the problems not forseen are overwhelming.  Although there are three pronged outlets in the clinic, none are really grounded.  Wiring to light fixtures appears as if done with bell wire. The WIFI unit in the school isn&amp;rsquo;t readily accessible (a minor problem). The clinic too needs some reorganization. A lot of donated stuff has been in boxes awaiting trained and eager hands to triage (yup triage) the medications. Overall it gets done.  Our primary server got mis directed in baggage and we&amp;rsquo;re waiting for it to be delivered. The secondary waits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jeff and I are staying at a Bed&amp;amp;Breakfast called &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.comeseeit.com&#34;&gt;Casa Manen&lt;/a&gt;, about a mile (all uphill) from the clinic. We&amp;rsquo;re getting used to the altitude, about 8500 ft here in Xela.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow we go to an outlying clinic about &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; of the way to Guatemala City to deliver health care to a small pueblo. We&amp;rsquo;ll be mounting the entire team plus medical students who are here to learn Spanish at Pop-Wuj. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of preparation and Jeff is going to look at the organization from a systems perspective to get better grounded to bring the records out side the clinic.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let them eat cruisers &amp;#8230;</title>
      <link>http://redlinedoc.com/2010/04/let-them-eat-cruisers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://redlinedoc.com/2010/04/let-them-eat-cruisers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The big boys at Chrysler appear to have &lt;a href=&#34;http://online.wsj.com/article/SB10001424052748704133804575197591370809782.html?mod=WSJ_newsreel_business#articleTabs_comments&#34;&gt;taken the pipe, 4 BILLION&lt;/a&gt; (with a &amp;lsquo;B&amp;rsquo; folks) in losses since exiting bankrupty! I doubt that will stop the executive piggies from snorting at the money trough in the name of needing to pay the best and brightest.&lt;br /&gt;
We need to remind ourselves that the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.glyphweb.com/arda/m/mouthofsauron.html&#34;&gt;Mouth of Sauron&lt;/a&gt; himself, the Chrysler damage control guy,  at meetings this past year said &amp;ldquo;Oh .. we put a bad engine in that car  &amp;ndash;  but  &amp;ndash;  (pregnant pause and I presume a wolfish smile), we don&amp;rsquo;t make them anymore.&amp;ldquo;  Not making one of the mechanically lousiest cars on the road is scarcely a strategy designed to win &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0071604/&#34;&gt;hearts and minds&lt;/a&gt; of Americans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The car had a sluggish start. It was very retro, very cute, very flawed.  The power train with an automatic could scarcely get the car out of its own way. Add a turbo and stickshift and it did go. Fixing the cars, it was my mechanic&amp;rsquo;s nightmare, was another thing. It would appear that the engine had been dropped into the car without regard for access. After all what fool would want to fix this?  Access to the engine required removing the right side of the car and all the steering gear there. The engine mounts blocked access to such non critical parts as the timing belt adjustment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I attended school at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.engr.uconn.edu/&#34;&gt;UCONN (University of Connecticut)&lt;/a&gt; which at the time had one of the finest civil and mechanical engineering departments in the country. I have friends from &lt;a href=&#34;http://web.mit.edu/&#34;&gt;MIT&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.caltech.edu/&#34;&gt;CALTECH&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.case.edu/&#34;&gt;CASE&lt;/a&gt; to name but a few. They seem pretty competent.  Is it possible there&amp;rsquo;s a large vacuum at Chrysler which sucks the smarts out of the engineering staff, followed closely by the moral vacuum which removes all traces of morality.   I have long thought that American ingenuity can solve most problems.  The difficulty is that American greed removes the problem solving substituting marketing glitz, &lt;a href=&#34;http://shakespeare.mit.edu/macbeth/macbeth.5.5.html&#34; title=&#34;Apologies to Shakespeare&#34;&gt;full of sound and fury, signifying, nothing. &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plunder me again</title>
      <link>http://redlinedoc.com/2010/04/plunder-me-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://redlinedoc.com/2010/04/plunder-me-again/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As I read Paul Krugman&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://community.nytimes.com/comments/www.nytimes.com/2010/04/19/opinion/19krugman.html?sort=highlights&amp;amp;offset=1&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Looters in Loafers&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;.i felt a bit prescient having blogged &lt;a href=&#34;lhttp://irv.ourexchange.net/2010/03/bonuses_for_bettors/&#34;&gt;Bonuses for Bettors &lt;/a&gt; before the current revelations. Perhaps that should be re-evaluations. Slippery as eels these folks, they fall back on &amp;hellip; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0413845/&#34;&gt;caveat emptor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;rdquo; although the only non-blinded fellows in the room were they. It was the impending release of poor&lt;a href=&#34;http://abcnews.go.com/Politics/Supreme_Court/enron-ceo-jeffrey-skilling-asks-supreme-court-trial/story?id=9954946&#34;&gt; Jeffrey&lt;/a&gt;, once the smartest guy in the room, realizing there were more cats to be skinned, er I mean folks to be fleeced. Well Jeff felt he got a raw deal and he, unable to wallow in the spoils.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When first I read of the looting and larceny I thought &lt;a href=&#34;http://headsonpikes.blogspot.com/&#34;&gt;&amp;#8216;heads on pikes&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#8216;; but I&amp;rsquo;m not blood thirsty enough for that. Then I watched Lehman implode and the jackals gather at the corpse to pick the sweet meats. Not one of them felt there was any wrong doing. Indeed they were all self righteous. At that time how little we knew.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve generally supported the aims of this administration (nationally), but find myself watching the the internal dealing and the Goldman-Sachs&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sfgate.com/cgi-bin/article.cgi?f=/g/a/2010/04/19/bloomberg1376-L152U61A1I4H-1.DTL&#34;&gt; revolving door spinning &lt;/a&gt;so fast its really a fan. I once saw a special about how an engineering firm kept their government work on one side of the hall and their civilian contracts on the other, claiming a &lt;a href=&#34;http://headsonpikes.blogspot.com/&#34;&gt;mehitza&lt;/a&gt; of sorts so that the engineers, who otherwise ate in the same mess facilities, used the same parking lots and other than sharing separate entryways, were really not at all co-mingled. Right.  When the former &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sfgate.com/cgi-bin/article.cgi?f=/g/a/2010/04/19/bloomberg1376-L152U61A1I4H-1.DTL&#34;&gt;chieftans&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sfgate.com/cgi-bin/article.cgi?f=/g/a/2010/04/19/bloomberg1376-L152U61A1I4H-1.DTL&#34;&gt;Goldman Sachs&lt;/a&gt; run not only the regulating agencies but are also judge and jury I wonder. Hmmm. Right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is not an &amp;#8216;appearance of wrongdoing&amp;rsquo;. It is offal on the table, and it would appear to be us, the American public. Perhaps I should revisit my former thoughts. Heads on pikes seem not so bad&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Health trek</title>
      <link>http://redlinedoc.com/2010/04/health-trek/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://redlinedoc.com/2010/04/health-trek/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;They trek in. They trek out. They stop, rest, disgorge their fantastic stories and let us help them; then out they go into the real world again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alas were this some fantasmagoric game. Its not. Its a Community Health Center.  We seem to collect them. Its partly our mission and partly our trial.  The health system in the United States has some serious problems those in power have yet to appreciate the depth of the hole, as it were.  If I were not at the center of the swirl, I would stand back and laugh at the machinations of those who worry that government will take over health care with disatrous results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are already at disastrous and the only thing that keeps us from total ruin are the government operated and funded programs.  I watched as our health center insurance, after all we too participate in the miasma of private for profit, stockholders take all insurance plans. Ours zipped up a mere 15% and still we face deductibles in the 1000&amp;#8242;s, expensive primary care deductibles and rules for use of additional services so arcane that even insurance people can&amp;rsquo;t figure it out. Kudos&amp;rsquo;s,  however, to my boss. He split off the rise so that the lowest paid on our staff paid the least percentage increase (perhaps 1-2%) and the highest paid 14-16% increases.  It makes an intolerable situation bearable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back to the ballyhoo. Government run programs including medicare and medicaid offer some of the best coverage for care, most uniform although occasionally tricky policies for patients and even on the reimbursement side. You know that if you provide services, sooner or later, within some guidelines you&amp;rsquo;ll get paid. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few years ago one of my private practice insurers sent a note out that the POB had changed for remittences to an adjacent town and another mail box. For most of us it was still the days of paper forms and humans not in call centers who worked the system. The box, no surprise, was a fake. After 4-6 weeks of languishing claims, the company began to get calls about where might be the remittances. After much furfuring, badinage and general lying, it came to light that some miscreant within the company had created this false address. Naughty man! Would we please resubmit the claims, which now had a current zero day for timing  &amp;ndash;  about two nearly three months out from their original date.  Someone made a boatload on that one!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The chicanery doesn&amp;rsquo;t end with the practitioners. The myriad of plans to medicare recipients, forced into a drug plan which is neither plan nor planned but a ponzi schema with a donut hole. For those of you sleeping under a rock for the past few years, the donut hole is a 5-7000 dollar shortfall which the medicare recipient must make up once the generosity of part D, we can&amp;rsquo;t negotiate price, plans have run out, leaving the senior holding bag, or readied to make the next payment on the stockholder&amp;rsquo;s investments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I offer a solution, its to step back from rhetoric and revisit a public option plan. Its not necessary to prop up the multinational corporations. We are the only quasi-civilized nation to be so hogtied by the greed of our corporations. To be sure other countries have found themselves, recently, at a shortfall because of the ill behaviour of organizations to big to fail, or perhaps to big to continue. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consider this:  the health of our citizens, much like their education is an investment in the future of our democracy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>At the end of all things.</title>
      <link>http://redlinedoc.com/2010/03/at-the-end-of-all-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://redlinedoc.com/2010/03/at-the-end-of-all-things/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sad faces. Sad days. We see the poorest of the poor at my&lt;a href=&#34;http://chshartford.org&#34;&gt; health center&lt;/a&gt;. Its a magnet for those who have nowhere else. We will see them. We do see them. We patch them up. We send them back into the fray, the madness that has become our world in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Neighborhoods_of_Hartford,_Connecticut&#34;&gt;north end of Hartford, Connecticut, &lt;/a&gt;only miles from the richest squares of land in the country. The disparity is at once engaging and maddening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some days ago a new face appeared in my care. Ragged on the edges, worn but still under the veneer of the street, a once proud person. She tells me she worked all her life, perhaps 40 years or more, receives &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ssa.gov/planners/calculators.htm&#34;&gt;Social Security&lt;/a&gt;, a pittance because she worked at one of the many downtown retail stores, making ends meet, and saving for retirement through a store plan. Prior to mall-ville, Hartford, as did many other cities, house a plethora of stores from &lt;a href=&#34;http://manuscripts.wordpress.com/category/g-fox-co/&#34;&gt;upscale department &lt;/a&gt;to&lt;a href=&#34;http://manuscripts.wordpress.com/category/g-fox-co/&#34;&gt; jewelry&lt;/a&gt; and electronic palaces. It was a mecca in its time. These folks and hundreds, nay thousands like them retired to small owned homes in the north end. Clean. Neat. A neighborhood in constant transition but with ties to religious and community organizations.  Then came &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dailyfinance.com/story/fraud-files-enrons-jeffrey-skilling-says-we-shouldnt-expect-e/19379616/&#34;&gt;Mr Skilling&lt;/a&gt; and his ilk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not content to raid the coffers of the gamblers of Wall Street, these folks conspired to use as tokens at the gambling tables the funds-in-trust for retirements. Now gone. Bankrupted. Disappeared.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She tells me that she couldn&amp;#8217;t afford the taxes on the house. Predators always scent prey in the winds of fortune. In her case it was a &amp;#8216;remortgage&amp;#8217; that promised to &amp;#8216;clear up the debt.&amp;#8217;  She lives in her car, however long that will last. She has no relatives in the area but has her &amp;#8216;church&amp;#8217; and her &amp;#8216;friends&amp;#8217; who don&amp;#8217;t know and she sent me a gimlet stare to let me know that I shouldn&amp;#8217;t consider letting them know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here we are at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wowhead.com/?quest=12779&#34;&gt;end of all things&lt;/a&gt;, accomplishing the American dream, living in our car.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>