<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Redline Doc</title>
    <link>http://redlinedoc.com/tags/goldman-sachs/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Redline Doc</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://redlinedoc.com/tags/goldman-sachs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Plunder me again</title>
      <link>http://redlinedoc.com/2010/04/plunder-me-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://redlinedoc.com/2010/04/plunder-me-again/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As I read Paul Krugman&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://community.nytimes.com/comments/www.nytimes.com/2010/04/19/opinion/19krugman.html?sort=highlights&amp;amp;offset=1&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Looters in Loafers&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;.i felt a bit prescient having blogged &lt;a href=&#34;lhttp://irv.ourexchange.net/2010/03/bonuses_for_bettors/&#34;&gt;Bonuses for Bettors &lt;/a&gt; before the current revelations. Perhaps that should be re-evaluations. Slippery as eels these folks, they fall back on &amp;hellip; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0413845/&#34;&gt;caveat emptor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;rdquo; although the only non-blinded fellows in the room were they. It was the impending release of poor&lt;a href=&#34;http://abcnews.go.com/Politics/Supreme_Court/enron-ceo-jeffrey-skilling-asks-supreme-court-trial/story?id=9954946&#34;&gt; Jeffrey&lt;/a&gt;, once the smartest guy in the room, realizing there were more cats to be skinned, er I mean folks to be fleeced. Well Jeff felt he got a raw deal and he, unable to wallow in the spoils.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When first I read of the looting and larceny I thought &lt;a href=&#34;http://headsonpikes.blogspot.com/&#34;&gt;&amp;#8216;heads on pikes&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#8216;; but I&amp;rsquo;m not blood thirsty enough for that. Then I watched Lehman implode and the jackals gather at the corpse to pick the sweet meats. Not one of them felt there was any wrong doing. Indeed they were all self righteous. At that time how little we knew.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve generally supported the aims of this administration (nationally), but find myself watching the the internal dealing and the Goldman-Sachs&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sfgate.com/cgi-bin/article.cgi?f=/g/a/2010/04/19/bloomberg1376-L152U61A1I4H-1.DTL&#34;&gt; revolving door spinning &lt;/a&gt;so fast its really a fan. I once saw a special about how an engineering firm kept their government work on one side of the hall and their civilian contracts on the other, claiming a &lt;a href=&#34;http://headsonpikes.blogspot.com/&#34;&gt;mehitza&lt;/a&gt; of sorts so that the engineers, who otherwise ate in the same mess facilities, used the same parking lots and other than sharing separate entryways, were really not at all co-mingled. Right.  When the former &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sfgate.com/cgi-bin/article.cgi?f=/g/a/2010/04/19/bloomberg1376-L152U61A1I4H-1.DTL&#34;&gt;chieftans&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sfgate.com/cgi-bin/article.cgi?f=/g/a/2010/04/19/bloomberg1376-L152U61A1I4H-1.DTL&#34;&gt;Goldman Sachs&lt;/a&gt; run not only the regulating agencies but are also judge and jury I wonder. Hmmm. Right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is not an &amp;#8216;appearance of wrongdoing&amp;rsquo;. It is offal on the table, and it would appear to be us, the American public. Perhaps I should revisit my former thoughts. Heads on pikes seem not so bad&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heads on pikes</title>
      <link>http://redlinedoc.com/2009/06/heads-on-pikes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://redlinedoc.com/2009/06/heads-on-pikes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It seems its a day of good news bad news. The good news seems to be that the boys at Goldman Sachs are snuffling at the trough and ready to suck up those great well deserved bonuses for having put us in the worst recession since the 30&amp;rsquo;s perhaps worse than that.  I fear that we missed an opportunity for heads on pikes. I&amp;rsquo;m not ordinarily a gory sort of fellow; however, if a few of those egregious folk had their heads up along the boulevard perhaps fewer of these guys would be snorting at the trough so soon. Its a sign that regulation has lost and that we as a nation have or will loose big time now that the game is a foot and the money is liberally flying around again.&lt;br /&gt;
It makes me wonder in some ways what the big call is for CEO&amp;rsquo;s. I hear one company after another looking for the most expensive CEO guy they can find. I have no problem paying for success. Its the paying for the failures. United Airlines, General Motors, Chrysler, Hewlett Packard &amp;ndash; each of those men and women walked away handsomely endowed with bonus and super bonus and stock options. As each of these companies tanked and drew down the economy we threw MORE money at CEO&amp;rsquo;s. I&amp;rsquo;ve yet to see cat skeleton&amp;rsquo;s around full cat food bowls.  I believe if we all went to reasonable executive pay and said NO MORE! that indeed CEO&amp;rsquo;s would be paid proportionately and reasonably. Perhaps we should make the CEO take some of the risk (not with fake-o securities from the board but with his own monies. Perhaps, as in days of yore, CEO&amp;rsquo;s should bear a percentage of risk and win-lose with the company.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Danny DeVito, ever a mirror for the times, did it well with &amp;ldquo;Other People&amp;rsquo;s Money&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Harvard business school recently announced that they might teach business ethics to their grads. What a concept! Such things as stealing from old ladies is wrong, wiping out the life savings of people and towns is poor for future business, and the future. My son said that if once in a while if the inchoate mob, those who lost nearly everything, had an opportunity to be in a closed area with the hedgies and mutualaholics who ground their savings from real to imaginary numbers that much of this would be object lesson.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But then, that&amp;rsquo;s pretty gory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Heads on pikes. Not a lot. Just a few. Some in Wall Street. Some on K Street. Some along the mall. Sobers the crowd and makes us remember that there really are people who are responsible. Until then, it&amp;rsquo;s still &amp;ldquo;Buddy can you spare a (discounted) dime.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>