<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Redline Doc</title>
    <link>http://redlinedoc.com/tags/health&#43;insurance/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Redline Doc</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://redlinedoc.com/tags/health&#43;insurance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>REAL Health care -- in the trenches.</title>
      <link>http://redlinedoc.com/2010/10/real-health-care-in-the-trenches/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://redlinedoc.com/2010/10/real-health-care-in-the-trenches/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I read Paul Romer&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://healthcareitstrategy.com/2010/10/12/the-effect-of-healthcare-reform-on-others-2/&#34;&gt;The effect of Health Care Reform&lt;/a&gt; on others, a play on the vagaries of our dysfunctional healthcare system and putative illnesses of &lt;a href=&#34;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mother_Goose&#34;&gt;Mother Goose&lt;/a&gt; characters.  I admit it (a guilty pleasure) I laughed. Then I reflected on the daily life in our&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.chshartford.org&#34;&gt; Community Health Center,&lt;/a&gt; in Connecticut, located in poorest city of its size in the nation. The irony is just too much. We &lt;a href=&#34;http://wiki.answers.com/Q/Why_is_connecticut_call_the_nutmeg_state&#34;&gt;(nutmegers)&lt;/a&gt; are the wealthiest per captita state in the nation!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But- I digress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A patient appears at our primary care clinic on Friday. Classic signs of cholecystitis (gall bladder attack).  We hustle her by transport to the emergency room. Monday morning she&amp;rsquo;s BACK!  At the emergency room, the nice physician gave her the name of several surgeons she could call to have her gall bladder fixed. None take her insurance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An 82 year old lady lives in her car. Bernie (this is too good) Madeoff with the retirement funding. She can&amp;rsquo;t afford the taxes. She lives in her car.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A patient comes for diabetic medication, gets a glucometer (to measure the sugar), strips (to use in the machine) but the company doesn&amp;rsquo;t pay for the lancets to draw the blood from the finger. Urmmmmmm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A patient drops a heavy object on her foot. She goes (of course) to the emergency room, diagnosed with a fracture but referred to the clinic so that she can have a cast put on.  She is uninsured.   I might add this over a five day period.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A patient comes with a kidney infection. No problem. Antibiotics. Oh  &amp;ndash;  we don&amp;rsquo;t cover THAT antibiotic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A patient, finally stabilized on psychiatric medication shows up for a refill. UhOh. You need a prior authorization. What? This patient has  been taking this for a year. No matter. We need to consider the forms (they say) to make sure the patient is getting the best medication. Insurance oversight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A letter arrived the other day from one of the major drug companies letting us know that they are going to be direct advertising to consumers for certain drugs so that they (the consumers) will know what best to ask for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A young boy comes having (as children are wont to do) leaped off a picnic table and stepped on some glass. The local ER (no problem) sees the child, recognizes that there is glass &amp;lsquo;somewhere&amp;rsquo; in the wound, sews up the wound, and sends the parents off in search of a surgeon who will see them on state insurance. Two days later. They arrive at our clinic looking for guidance. We are fortunate to have some favors to call in. He gets care.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lest you think out there that is is a factor of my particular city, its not. As I speak with colleagues around the country, this is the rule not the exception. As insurers tighten the profit noose, looking to their bottom lines not yours, this is a frightening and every more common occurrence. As hospital emergency room expenses rise the quest to slide more care out to the community increases. Its shoddy. Its terrible. Its not good medicine, hell its not good care in the third world. It is however our current system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Healthcare reform may change some of this but we are only at a beginning. I praise Paul for bringing a bit of humour to what is, for me, a very black, dark sad subject.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>it couldn&#39;t hurt .. or could it</title>
      <link>http://redlinedoc.com/2010/10/it-couldnt-hurt-or-could-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://redlinedoc.com/2010/10/it-couldnt-hurt-or-could-it/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been watching with interest the current Republican party dance around repeal of the Healthcare insurance legislation just passed.  Its a sad bit of badly made political salad with very little for those who need health insurance, a guaranteed business for the insurance companies (universal sign up), &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slate.com/id/2224621/&#34; title=&#34;Big Pharma Billy Tauzin&#34;&gt;guaranteed pharma profits (no pharma negotiation) &lt;/a&gt;and extension of the market for about 40% of those who are still uncovered or uninsured.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;State legislatures, not to be overlooked are trying their best to carve themselves in our out of the new Heatlhcare bill by blocking advances or by shouting states rights.  With hard economic times, its easy to get voters to hear the shouting but miss the salient points.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve missed the boat, again. Smoke and mirrors and distraction reign supreme. The emperor, or his bill, have no clothes. This does not cover a majority of the uninsured. I&amp;rsquo;m waiting to see how those who are unemployed, now some approaching the 2 year mark, will pay for this bit of fluff.  The state&amp;rsquo;s assistance systems were already at a foundering point and shoving the burden to physicians and hospitals for the under and uninsured will only exacerbate the problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a bit of shuck and drag going on here. We&amp;rsquo;re told that we need to work to pass this. We&amp;rsquo;re told it will bankrupt us. We&amp;rsquo;re told this is socialism at its worst.  Socialism?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today one of the walking wounded comes to the clinic. She works 40-50 hours a week, full time  she&amp;rsquo;s told, at one of the local hospitals. To expedite services the hospital contracts out its housekeeping. The firm, to keep profits ripe,  they don&amp;rsquo;t pay insurance.  Hmm. Ok. We took what was a paid in-house position, took away the benefits, hired the same folks to do the same job so that the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=p220yi2VOj8&#34; title=&#34;I was gonna  be an engineer &#34;&gt;profits would stay as high as maybe &lt;/a&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I digress. Here&amp;rsquo;s a full time working person with no insurance.  How is a public option for her, socialism?  From where I sit, we pay into the medicare system.  We pay it in wages and taxes and reap a long term benefit devoid of the need for stockholders to benefit. Although an inconstant fiduciary, generally governments have handled trust funds much better than banks or insurance companies, always looking to the next gaming table, ripening the profits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we allow the loud shouts to take back the minimal advances, and I agree its far from perfect, we&amp;rsquo;ll end up with still more uninsured.  The hidden cost of the &amp;lsquo;uninsured&amp;rsquo; long patched over by draining high end payments from private insurers into the unbalanced pot is at an end. The insurance blokes, have cut off that avenue. The uninsured now go to emergency rooms, expensive care, and not much of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Emphasis from the Healthcare Plan was on primary care, extending to patients the ability to see and to find competent expert medical care. If we persist at deconstructing the fragile imperfect house, we&amp;rsquo;ll have but a very expensive house of cards fallen loosely and very expensively apart.  Threats of Medicare cuts are more thunder than substance. We do need government to help us. Watch carefully.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Turfed too</title>
      <link>http://redlinedoc.com/2009/08/turfed-too/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://redlinedoc.com/2009/08/turfed-too/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It amazes me that in the land of&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2007/08/12/opinion/12sun1.html&#34;&gt; the best healthcare&lt;/a&gt; we&amp;rsquo;re more in the business of denying care than providing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I get a call the other day that a kid has stepped on a piece of glass. Its off hours but I say &amp;ldquo;sure, bring him in, I&amp;rsquo;ll take a look&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A pale frightened 13y/o arrives at the clinic with parents. Apparently yesterday he jumped up off a picnic table (in the way that 13 year old males do) and sprang directly onto a wine glass lying on the ground. The glass shattered into the bottom of his foot. The parents, correctly, take him to the nearest emergency room. He waits approximately 3 &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; hours since its &amp;ldquo;only a bleeding foot&amp;rdquo;. Xrays show glass in the wound and the physician diagnoses tendon injuries to the tendons of the toes. Ahh, you say, a case for the surgeons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not so fast. He has a state option child health insurance. They sew up the foot (with the glass inside) and direct him to a private practice clinic the following day. He continues to bleed, slowly, through the night. Mom and dad pack him off to the local recommended doctor only to find that he (nor most others) do not accept this insurance. They are tempted to return to the emergency room but call me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He cannot be treated here. He needs advanced care which we cannot offer to him. I make some calls with the assistance of our pediatrician. He&amp;rsquo;s transferred to a tertiary care facility. By 4PM he&amp;rsquo;s in an operating room and being cared for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What went wrong? Why didn&amp;rsquo;t the emergency room transfer him inter-hospital when they realized they had a severe injury they couldn&amp;rsquo;t handle? Why did they refer him through out patient when clearly there was no real outpatient option?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Insurance. When the insurance pays so poorly that even the most basic of services are covered but lose money, then the hospitals, left to chose to bleed monies or to restrict services chose the latter. In the land of &amp;#8216;the best healthcare&amp;rdquo; we are forced into rationing that healthcare based not on need, not on priorities but on the needs of the stockholders of insurance companies.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>