<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Redline Doc</title>
    <link>http://redlinedoc.com/categories/commentary/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Redline Doc</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://redlinedoc.com/categories/commentary/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>it couldn&#39;t hurt .. or could it</title>
      <link>http://redlinedoc.com/2010/10/it-couldnt-hurt-or-could-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://redlinedoc.com/2010/10/it-couldnt-hurt-or-could-it/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been watching with interest the current Republican party dance around repeal of the Healthcare insurance legislation just passed.  Its a sad bit of badly made political salad with very little for those who need health insurance, a guaranteed business for the insurance companies (universal sign up), &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slate.com/id/2224621/&#34; title=&#34;Big Pharma Billy Tauzin&#34;&gt;guaranteed pharma profits (no pharma negotiation) &lt;/a&gt;and extension of the market for about 40% of those who are still uncovered or uninsured.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;State legislatures, not to be overlooked are trying their best to carve themselves in our out of the new Heatlhcare bill by blocking advances or by shouting states rights.  With hard economic times, its easy to get voters to hear the shouting but miss the salient points.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve missed the boat, again. Smoke and mirrors and distraction reign supreme. The emperor, or his bill, have no clothes. This does not cover a majority of the uninsured. I&amp;rsquo;m waiting to see how those who are unemployed, now some approaching the 2 year mark, will pay for this bit of fluff.  The state&amp;rsquo;s assistance systems were already at a foundering point and shoving the burden to physicians and hospitals for the under and uninsured will only exacerbate the problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a bit of shuck and drag going on here. We&amp;rsquo;re told that we need to work to pass this. We&amp;rsquo;re told it will bankrupt us. We&amp;rsquo;re told this is socialism at its worst.  Socialism?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today one of the walking wounded comes to the clinic. She works 40-50 hours a week, full time  she&amp;rsquo;s told, at one of the local hospitals. To expedite services the hospital contracts out its housekeeping. The firm, to keep profits ripe,  they don&amp;rsquo;t pay insurance.  Hmm. Ok. We took what was a paid in-house position, took away the benefits, hired the same folks to do the same job so that the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=p220yi2VOj8&#34; title=&#34;I was gonna  be an engineer &#34;&gt;profits would stay as high as maybe &lt;/a&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I digress. Here&amp;rsquo;s a full time working person with no insurance.  How is a public option for her, socialism?  From where I sit, we pay into the medicare system.  We pay it in wages and taxes and reap a long term benefit devoid of the need for stockholders to benefit. Although an inconstant fiduciary, generally governments have handled trust funds much better than banks or insurance companies, always looking to the next gaming table, ripening the profits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we allow the loud shouts to take back the minimal advances, and I agree its far from perfect, we&amp;rsquo;ll end up with still more uninsured.  The hidden cost of the &amp;lsquo;uninsured&amp;rsquo; long patched over by draining high end payments from private insurers into the unbalanced pot is at an end. The insurance blokes, have cut off that avenue. The uninsured now go to emergency rooms, expensive care, and not much of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Emphasis from the Healthcare Plan was on primary care, extending to patients the ability to see and to find competent expert medical care. If we persist at deconstructing the fragile imperfect house, we&amp;rsquo;ll have but a very expensive house of cards fallen loosely and very expensively apart.  Threats of Medicare cuts are more thunder than substance. We do need government to help us. Watch carefully.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shelley Runs Demi Marathon</title>
      <link>http://redlinedoc.com/2010/09/shelley-runs-demi-marathon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://redlinedoc.com/2010/09/shelley-runs-demi-marathon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I don´t have pictures yet but Shelley ran with John Sullivan in a (billed as 26 km) race through the streets of &lt;a href=&#34;es.wikipedia.org/wiki/Quetzaltenango&#34;&gt;Xela&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The race began a bit late and Dr. Sullivan and I were watching on street corners for the racers.  Its 2600 meteres up here so the air is thin.  Things done Guatemaltecan style are often without much preparation. There were no crossing guards, no blockoff´s to run interference for the &lt;a href=&#34;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chicken_bus&#34;&gt;Chicken Bus&lt;/a&gt; population and the cars seemed relatively oblivous of the racers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hills were daunting. The traffic next to the runners spewed dark deisel fumes as the racers coughed and ran.  Motorcycles, always taking the smaller parts of the road roared by .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were able to watch the race from four vantage points  &amp;ndash;  the last so close to the finish line that  I didn´t get to photograph Shelley at the finish.  She insists that the race was only a 15k but she finished and she and John were sore but happy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pictures I hope later and a short video as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Signing off for a bit until I can get to pictures and uploads.   Do check out my Flickr page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hola&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>And the dirt falls...</title>
      <link>http://redlinedoc.com/2009/07/and-the-dirt-falls/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://redlinedoc.com/2009/07/and-the-dirt-falls/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today we buried a cat. Not just a cat but a family cat of 14+ years. She came to us as a small fur bundle, not a handful, not eyes open yet, abandoned mewling. We tiger milk fed her with noises from the kids about what a pain she was .. .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And she became ours. She was first and foremost my daughter Shelley&amp;rsquo;s cat, sleeping with her, cuddling with her being her special friend through out her teen years. She was always a second tier cat until last August when the lead cat, Hobbes left us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, as I dug the hole, a mitzvah, a good and special deed, and had help from my guys from Adam and from Jeff, making the hole deep enough wide enough to fit the box. We&amp;rsquo;d stored the cat in the freezer waiting for everyone to gather. She&amp;rsquo;s our last cat, last animal. We&amp;rsquo;ve lost many, dogs, fish ,birds, iguana, and cats. We&amp;rsquo;ve never been without some animal in the house even in our earliest days with gerbils (from graduate school) and then Svivon the cat who came to visit with us only for a short time. There was Anhanya who we adopted (let me tell you its easier to adopt children) and she stayed with us for nearly 23 years! So here we are &amp;hellip; just us. The no kids thing we&amp;rsquo;ve adjusted to. They come home and we&amp;rsquo;re always glad to see them. But they leave and go to their own lives and their own fortunes and their own households and all of them have pets. Petless we are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But as I dug the hole, I had a flash of my own mortality, of being IN the hole .. of hearing the dirt splash on me, of being covered of being morned and I can&amp;rsquo;t shake it. Its like a wet blanket. Despite a friend who came for the day, despite the children, despite Brenda &amp;ndash; its hard to shake that cold feeling. And then to top that off, in the boom box parade, there was this specter, death pulling the death wagon and it was, for me, very real.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know it will pass as will the mourning. I know we will search for another animal &amp;ndash; we&amp;rsquo;d both love a dog but know that we&amp;rsquo;re really not at the level to care for such a responsibility another family member but we shall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Annie was a good cat. I miss her&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dead chickens. No eggs.</title>
      <link>http://redlinedoc.com/2009/06/dead-chickens-no-eggs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://redlinedoc.com/2009/06/dead-chickens-no-eggs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was recently reminded that leaving weasels in the hen house gives you a result. Alas, its dead chickens and no eggs.  Why chickens?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our economic (heaven forfend czars) have been running in and out of the hen house. I had proposed, and I&amp;rsquo;m not a gory fellow, that perhaps a few heads-on-pikes outside Lehman Brothers might have curtailed the mad stealing that goes on. Yes, I&amp;rsquo;m a victim too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each day I read of the glorious rounds of &lt;a href=&#34;http://http://www.alternet.org/story/140327/?page=entire&#34;&gt;in the front out the back door&lt;/a&gt; dealing at the SEC with Larry Summers or the folks at Chrysler or GM who revel in the bailout, glory in bankruptcy.  A few days ago the VP of Chrysler said in effect sorry folks we made some lousy cars, like the PT Crusier, it had a lousy engine but they sold!&amp;#8230;. and I an owner of one of those lumps of clay!  There is some &lt;a href=&#34;http://blogs.reuters.com/reuters-dealzone/2009/06/02/bankruptcy-means-never-having-to-say-sorry/&#34;&gt;chutzpah in the GM&lt;/a&gt; folks managing NOT to take any responsibility for anything. Its the fault of unions, economy, dealers, stockholders, manufacturers of parts but no no no not GM. They didn&amp;rsquo;t make cars that didn&amp;rsquo;t run, engines that failed for obvious reasons, cars that fell apart nearly on the lots,  no no no not them. Its someone else&amp;rsquo;s fault. Those same donkeys are going to be rebuilding the same cars but with our monies. What a way to go. Take a risk. Do a lousy job. Get a bailout!    Hmmm is there a DD-285/7448  that -=I=- can get to fill in for my share?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indeed all the folks are all white-washed now. Not to worry. Stole a few million in pension funds from old folks to gamble away with 100:1 odds? Didn&amp;rsquo;t see it coming? Naah not to worry Mr Weasel, here are the keys.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what. They&amp;rsquo;re old. They didn&amp;rsquo;t need the eggs anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>